<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mac on chapter31</title>
    <link>http://chapter31.com/categories/mac/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mac on chapter31</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; &lt;a href=&#34;http://michaelsharman.com&#34;&gt;Michael Sharman&lt;/a&gt; 2017</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://chapter31.com/categories/mac/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache permission denied on Mac OSX Lion</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2012/06/05/apache-permission-denied-on-mac-osx-lion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2012/06/05/apache-permission-denied-on-mac-osx-lion/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve just upgraded to OSX Lion and had some trouble getting Apache to load a vhost. I kept getting a 403 permission denied error, but all my vhosts had the correct permission directives set.
Now by default your webserver document root is located in /Library/WebServer/Documents. I don&amp;rsquo;t really like that for my local machine, I&amp;rsquo;d rather store web files under my user account. Just tends to make things easier.
However&amp;hellip;if you&amp;rsquo;re getting a 403 error, and something like this in your apache error log (/var/log/apache2/error_log):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strange linefeed characters appearing on Mac</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2012/05/24/strange-linefeed-characters-appearing-on-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2012 04:14:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2012/05/24/strange-linefeed-characters-appearing-on-mac/</guid>
      <description>Had a funny situation today where I was emailed a bash program file, but simply downloading the attachment from gmail (in Chrome) added a linefeed (\r) to the file.
This is strange because I never actually opened the file to edit, so I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what was writing those chars to the file. I&amp;rsquo;m on a Mac (OSX 10.6.8), so I get the line feed character in general, but just not in this case as the file was never opened.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turning voice over off permanently on Max OSX</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2012/03/14/turning-voice-over-off-permanently-on-max-osx/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2012 05:41:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2012/03/14/turning-voice-over-off-permanently-on-max-osx/</guid>
      <description>One of the keyboard shortcuts I often use is command-F6, but I seem to accidentally hit command-F5 on most occasions :(
Problem with this is that the god awful &amp;ldquo;voice over&amp;rdquo; starts yapping away. Well if you&amp;rsquo;re like me and know that you&amp;rsquo;ll pretty much never want this enabled (at least for now!) then here&amp;rsquo;s how you turn it off permanently.
 Open up system preferences Click on keyboard Go to the keyboard shortcuts tab Choose universal access from the list on the left Uncheck the &amp;ldquo;Turn voice over on or off&amp;rdquo; checkbox  Breathe a sigh of relief :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Importing a csv into MySQL using the command line</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2010/11/14/importing-a-csv-into-mysql-using-the-command-line/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2010 23:38:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2010/11/14/importing-a-csv-into-mysql-using-the-command-line/</guid>
      <description>UPDATE 16th Nov 2010: I had some issues with the import which I noted in the first code example below
Today I had to import csv into a single mysql table. The destination table only had 5 columns and the csv was around 22MB (around 400,000 records). The csv also contained more columns that I needed for the import. Sometimes I&amp;rsquo;ll use a GUI to do this as I usually have one open, but it never ceases to amaze me how much slower GUI tools are compared to the command line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Case sensitive development on Mac OS X</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2010/10/04/case-sensitive-development-on-mac-os-x/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2010/10/04/case-sensitive-development-on-mac-os-x/</guid>
      <description>At work most of the developers are on Mac OS X but our staging and production environments are Linux based. This means development is case insensitive but stage/production is case sensitive. Although we have development guidelines/standards which dictate file and database naming conventions etc, human error can still occur (in terms of referencing files with a different &amp;ldquo;case&amp;rdquo;). We also use a few open source packages where we obviously don&amp;rsquo;t have control over the naming of files or the references to database tables within those files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Inkscape (0.46) to run on Mac Leopard</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/08/06/getting-inkscape-046-to-run-on-mac-leopard/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2008 01:09:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/08/06/getting-inkscape-046-to-run-on-mac-leopard/</guid>
      <description>Inscape is a fantastic open source vector graphics tool which can be a nice alternative to Adobe&amp;rsquo;s Illustrator.
Getting it to run on the Mac took a couple of extra steps though.
Firstly the download page advises that you upgrade X11.app to at least XQuartz v2.1.4. This is a large-ish download which forces you to quit all applications as it needs to restart your system after installing.
The next problem was that after a restart, Inkscape displays a message saying that the first time it runs it may take a while to load as it needs to caches fonts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do you lock your screen on a Mac?</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/07/22/how-do-you-lock-your-screen-on-a-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/07/22/how-do-you-lock-your-screen-on-a-mac/</guid>
      <description>Call me crazy, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem like you can &amp;ldquo;natively&amp;rdquo; lock your screen on a Mac like you can on Windows. Very odd and annoying as it&amp;rsquo;s something I do everytime I leave my workstation, I&amp;rsquo;ve even had to agree to a policy that I will never leave my workstation open as I have secure access to production servers (via ssh).
I found some craziness on google where users setup &amp;ldquo;hot corners&amp;rdquo; with mouse gestures with the idea that when you &amp;ldquo;drag your cursor&amp;rdquo; into that corner the screensaver will be activated requiring a password to get back to the desktop.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>