<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on chapter31</title>
    <link>http://chapter31.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on chapter31</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; &lt;a href=&#34;http://michaelsharman.com&#34;&gt;Michael Sharman&lt;/a&gt; 2017</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://chapter31.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Sonar Source on Mac OSX – Part 2</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2015/06/30/installing-sonar-source-on-mac-osx-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2015/06/30/installing-sonar-source-on-mac-osx-part-2/</guid>
      <description>I had some notes a while ago for installing Sonar on a Mac. Recently I upgraded to a new Mac, OS X Yosemite (10.10.3), and found I needed to add a few steps to the install process.
 You need the JDK to run Sonar You need xdebug  xdebug To install xdebug run:
sudo pecl install xdebug  Then add to your php.ini the following (I just added it to the bottom), replace the version in the path with whichever you installed:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disabling the Flash plugin for testing</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2015/05/29/disabling-the-flash-plugin-for-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2015/05/29/disabling-the-flash-plugin-for-testing/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes you want to test things without the Flash plugin enabled, using Chrome this is nice and easy!
Just type chrome://plugins/ in the address bar to open the Chrome plugin settings page. Should look something like:
Note the Adobe Flash Player on the last line, just disable that and you&amp;rsquo;re good to go. Don&amp;rsquo;t even need a browser restart, just a new tab.
You can test this using Adobe&amp;rsquo;s Flash Player Help page</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing VirtualBox Guest Additions</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2015/05/17/installing-virtualbox-guest-additions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2015/05/17/installing-virtualbox-guest-additions/</guid>
      <description>Currently I have VirtualBox 4.3.18 installed on Mac OS X Mavericks. I recently downloaded several Windows 7/8/8.1 images from either modern.ie or MSDN, and I wanted to install guest additions as well so I could do things like:
 change the size of the guest window turn on bidirectional shared clipboard add shared folder(s) etc  There is a handy menu option to do this from the VirtualBox VM menu:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Opening .eml files on a mac</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2015/05/06/opening-eml-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2015/05/06/opening-eml-files/</guid>
      <description>More and more I&amp;rsquo;m getting emails from clients with .eml attachments. These are generally email messages created by Microsoft Outlook and may contain their own attachments (files or images etc).
The issue for me is that I don&amp;rsquo;t use Outlook&amp;hellip;but I still need to find a way to open them, ideally a way that includes accessing the original attachments.
Luckily there are a several options, including (first download the eml file):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple JSON prettify</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2013/12/16/simple-json-prettify/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2013/12/16/simple-json-prettify/</guid>
      <description>I went looking for a quick and easy way to style JSON content for display in the browser and quickly came across this answer at stack overflow with a corresponding jsfiddle entry.
However the problem is that this is kinda broken, the output isn&amp;rsquo;t valid JSON because the keys aren&amp;rsquo;t quoted. It&amp;rsquo;s just outputting a JavaScript object intead. A quick fix (and slight refactor) to the JavaScript gave me what I needed, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t post on SO as I don&amp;rsquo;t have the reputation (yeah that&amp;rsquo;s annoying) so I&amp;rsquo;m posting here for reference and I forked the original JSFiddle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Careful using PHP array_merge</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2013/06/22/careful-using-php-array-merge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2013/06/22/careful-using-php-array-merge/</guid>
      <description>Using array_merge bit me today when I merged an array (which happened to be empty) with a numerically indexed array.
Because the array I was merging was empty, I expected my other (numerically indexed) array to remain untouched. However that wasn&amp;rsquo;t the case, from the docs:
Values in the input array with numeric keys will be renumbered with incrementing keys starting from zero in the result array.  This meant that the following array keys went from being their constant numeric values, to 0, 1, 2, 3:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHP [&#39;SCRIPT_NAME&#39;] returning empty string</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2013/06/21/php-script-name-returning-empty-string/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2013/06/21/php-script-name-returning-empty-string/</guid>
      <description>I was working with Slim (v2.2.x) the other day and saw that a PHP warning was being thrown in one of the interal Slim files:
Warning: strpos(): Empty needle in /vendor/slim/slim/Slim/Environment.php on line 143  The code throwing the warning was the following if statement:
if (strpos($_SERVER[&#39;REQUEST_URI&#39;], $_SERVER[&#39;SCRIPT_NAME&#39;]) === 0) {  The actual issue was that $_SERVER[&#39;SCRIPT_NAME&#39;] was an empty string, so strpos was complaining as that is invalid syntax.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Problem dumping MySQL database - Unknown system variable &#39;GTID_MODE&#39;</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2013/06/19/problem-dumping-mysql-database-unknown-system-variable-gtid-mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2013/06/19/problem-dumping-mysql-database-unknown-system-variable-gtid-mode/</guid>
      <description>I was trying to dump and restore a MySQL database today, but received the following error when I tried to dump:
mysqldump: Couldn&#39;t execute &#39;SELECT @@GTID_MODE&#39;: Unknown system variable &#39;GTID_MODE&#39; (1193)  The MySQL version of the database I was trying to dump was 5.5.28 and the server I was trying to restore into was 5.6.10.
A quick google told me that the error was likely due to this mismatch in versions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>INI Syntax Highlighting in Sublime Text</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2013/06/13/ini-syntax-highlighting-in-sublime-text/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2013/06/13/ini-syntax-highlighting-in-sublime-text/</guid>
      <description>I went searching for a package to provide syntax highlighting for INI files in Sublime Text. The reason? INI files are ugly ;(
I found one that works well called sublime-text-2-ini.
Installation isn&amp;rsquo;t done via the package manager, but it&amp;rsquo;s still simple. Open a terminal and navigate to your Sublime Packages folder, then clone in the package from github.
cd ~/Library/Application\ Support/Sublime\ Text\ 2/Packages/ git clone git@github.com:clintberry/sublime-text-2-ini.git ./INI  That&amp;rsquo;s it!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Error writing git commit messages with vi</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2013/06/08/error-writing-git-commit-messages-with-vi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2013/06/08/error-writing-git-commit-messages-with-vi/</guid>
      <description>I typically write my git commit messages in the terminal, but today I wanted to write a multi-line comment so I left out the -m argument to git commit so it would open up my default editor, which is vi:
git commit  I wrote my comment, saved and exit but got an error:
$ git commit error: There was a problem with the editor &#39;vi&#39;. Please supply the message using either -m or -F option.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHP Composer error - cannot redeclare class</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2013/06/03/php-composer-error-cannot-redeclare-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2013/06/03/php-composer-error-cannot-redeclare-class/</guid>
      <description>I rebuilt PHP last night to include APC and all of a sudden composer stopped working in my project. Whenever I ran a simple update, install or dump-autoload I&amp;rsquo;d get:
$ composer update PHP Fatal error: include(): Cannot redeclare class symfony\component\process\process in phar:///usr/local/bin/composer/vendor/composer/ClassLoader.php on line 183 Fatal error: include(): Cannot redeclare class symfony\component\process\process in phar:///usr/local/bin/composer/vendor/composer/ClassLoader.php on line 183  A quick google told me others also had the same issue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing APC in PHP 5.4.x on Mac OSX</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2013/06/02/installing-apc-in-php-5-dot-4-x-on-mac-osx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2013/06/02/installing-apc-in-php-5-dot-4-x-on-mac-osx/</guid>
      <description>I recently installed PHP 5.4 from source but needed to add APC.
Most people can install this using PECL, but I got an error doing this:
$ pecl install apc Warning: lstat(): Lstat failed for /private/tmp/pear/cache/497e483d585c1e3f341260e73a8c6e85rest.cacheid in PEAR/REST.php on line 276 Warning: lstat(): Lstat failed for /private/tmp/pear/cache/497e483d585c1e3f341260e73a8c6e85rest.cacheid in /opt/php-5.4.15/lib/php/PEAR/REST.php on line 276 No releases available for package &amp;quot;pecl.php.net/apc&amp;quot; install failed  So instead I downloaded the APC source from the PECL website and ran the following:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>base16 - colour scheme for hackers</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2013/06/01/base16-colour-scheme-for-hackers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2013/06/01/base16-colour-scheme-for-hackers/</guid>
      <description>I came across a great set of colour schemes called base16. From the website:
Base16 provides carefully chosen syntax highlighting and a default set of sixteen colors suitable for a wide range of applications. Base16 is both a color scheme and a template.  There are repos for the following tools:
 Base 16 Builder Vim Shell iTerm2 TextMate OSX Color Palette Xresources Mou XFCE4 Terminal Gimp Palette Gnome Terminal Emacs Geany  There&amp;rsquo;s even a builder so you can roll your own theme!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Xdebug on Mac Mountain Lion (10.8.3)</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2013/05/29/installing-xdebug-on-mac-mountain-lion-10-dot-8-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2013/05/29/installing-xdebug-on-mac-mountain-lion-10-dot-8-3/</guid>
      <description>Even though I&amp;rsquo;m running Mountain Lion (10.8.3) which comes with Xdebug I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get the PHP (5.4.14) local web server to register that Xdebug was actually installed and enabled.
My php.ini had the already installed Xdebug extension enabled:
zend_extension=&amp;quot;/usr/lib/php/extensions/no-debug-non-zts-20090626/xdebug.so&amp;quot;  But whenever I inspected phpinfo() there wasn&amp;rsquo;t any mention of Xdebug.
Luckily the website has a wizard where you can paste the output of phpinfo(). From there you get detailed instructions on how to download, configure and make the latest version of Xdebug.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MySQL thread_stack overrun error</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2013/05/22/mysql-thread-stack-overrun-error/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2013/05/22/mysql-thread-stack-overrun-error/</guid>
      <description>We added a trigger to MySQL (v5.5.28) recently that was a simple UPDATE on table column, when a target table was UPDATEd. It ran fine (as expected) on our development environment but not when we pushed the changes to staging.
The error being thrown by MySQL was:
Thread stack overrun: 8304 bytes used of a 131072 byte stack, and 128000 bytes needed. Use &#39;mysqld --thread_stack=#&#39; to specify a bigger stack.  Querying the database told me that the current _threadstack setting is 128K:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iOS 6 caching POST requests</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2013/05/09/ios-6-caching-post-requests/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2013/05/09/ios-6-caching-post-requests/</guid>
      <description>Apparently I&amp;rsquo;ve been living under a rock, never having been bitten (that I know of) by the pretty massive bug Apple rolled out in iOS 6 (with Safari). The bug has been well documented around the interwebs, basically Safari caches HTTP POST requests. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t heard about this&amp;hellip;stop and read that last bit again.
Now, replicating this bug is dependent on the payload of the POST not changing between requests, so in many circumstances you may be fine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrating from bitbucket to github</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2013/05/08/migrating-from-bitbucket-to-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2013/05/08/migrating-from-bitbucket-to-github/</guid>
      <description>Migrating repositories between bitbucket and github couldn&amp;rsquo;t be simpler thanks to the design nature of DVCS like git because the entire history is already located on your machine within your projects .git folder. All you&amp;rsquo;re really doing is changing a remote.
Open a terminal and navigate to your project directory.
TLDR; For those who just want the commands with no explanation
git remote rename origin bitbucket git remote add origin git@github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Date timezone error when upgrading to PHP 5.3&#43;</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2013/05/06/date-timezone-error-when-upgrading-to-php-5-dot-3-plus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2013/05/06/date-timezone-error-when-upgrading-to-php-5-dot-3-plus/</guid>
      <description>I upgraded to 5.4.14 last night on Mac OSX 10.8.3. Things went smoothly except I got an error running my apps:
 date(): It is not safe to rely on the system&amp;rsquo;s timezone settings. You are required to use the date.timezone setting or the date_default_timezone_set() function. In case you used any of those methods and you are still getting this warning, you most likely misspelled the timezone identifier. We selected the timezone &amp;lsquo;UTC&amp;rsquo; for now, but please set date.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing PHP 5.4&#43; from source on Mac OSX Mountain Lion</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2013/05/06/installing-php-5-dot-4-plus-from-source-on-mac-mountain-lion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2013/05/06/installing-php-5-dot-4-plus-from-source-on-mac-mountain-lion/</guid>
      <description>Download and extract the PHP source from php.net, for me that was 5.4.14. Put it somewhere friendly, the desktop will do.
Open a terminal and install some dependancies via brew:
brew install libjpeg brew install pcre brew install libxml2 brew install mcrypt  Download and install ICU from http://site.icu-project.org/download/48#ICU4C-Download
tar xzvf icu4c-4_8_1-src.tgz cd icu/source ./runConfigureICU MacOSX make sudo make install  Rebuild IMAP, download source from ftp://ftp.cac.washington.edu/imap/
make osx EXTRACFLAGS=&amp;quot;-arch i386 -arch x86_64 -g -Os -pipe -no-cpp-precomp&amp;quot; sudo cp c-client/*.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stopping a remote process after killing an ssh session</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2013/05/05/stopping-a-remote-process-after-killing-an-ssh-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2013/05/05/stopping-a-remote-process-after-killing-an-ssh-session/</guid>
      <description>I often want to tail log files on remote server(s) when running diagnostics for an application. You can either login to the remote server via an SSH session, then execute the tail command. Or you can do it from a local shell (without explicitly logging onto the remote server first). That&amp;rsquo;s pretty simple:
ssh myRemoteServer tail -f /path/to/logs/myapp.log  The problem here, is when you ctrl-c out of this command to kill the tail, the process is still running on the remote machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing sonar source on Mac OSX</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2013/05/02/installing-sonar-source-on-mac-osx/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2013/05/02/installing-sonar-source-on-mac-osx/</guid>
      <description>Update 30 June 2015
Part 2 is here with further instructions
&amp;ndash;
Sonar Source is a an open source, browser based tool to manage code quality. You download and install it, setup some language specific plugins then let it loose on your codebase.
It basically reports on data generated by doing a static analysis of your code on things like:
 Duplicate code Comment coverage Coding rules Unit tests Code complexity etc  Installing it on a Mac is relatively painless, but there are quite a few steps to follow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding a global ignore file for git</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2013/01/21/adding-a-global-ignore-file-for-git/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2013 12:02:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2013/01/21/adding-a-global-ignore-file-for-git/</guid>
      <description>Quick setup of ignore files for Git. You can of course set these up per repo, but that gets a little old. Instead you can setup a single ignore file and link to it so that every repo refers to it.
For example, create a git ignore file in your home directory:
~/.gitignore_global  Fill it with regular files that you want to ignore:
#.gitignore # Railo files # ###################### WEB-INF/ # Sublime files # ###################### *.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Showing hidden files in Finder on mac osx</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2013/01/21/showing-hidden-files-in-finder-on-mac-osx/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2013 11:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2013/01/21/showing-hidden-files-in-finder-on-mac-osx/</guid>
      <description>Short and sweet, MAC OSX has this annoying trait where hidden files (dotfiles) are not visible by default in Finder. No probs, I&amp;rsquo;ll just go to the &amp;ldquo;View&amp;rdquo; menu and turn them on. Nope&amp;hellip;nada, zip.
Turns out you have to enter a command in the terminal, nice. Here it is for future reference:
defaults write com.apple.finder AppleShowAllFiles TRUE  Then kill Finder to have the changes take effect.
killall Finder  If you ever want to turn hidden files off?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Downloading youtube videos</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2013/01/01/downloading-youtube-videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 02:48:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2013/01/01/downloading-youtube-videos/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to grab some youtube videos for the kids and found this cool CLI utility called youtube-dl to handle it. I downloaded it from the website (you may need to chmod 755):
wget https://github.com/downloads/rg3/youtube-dl/youtube-dl -O /usr/local/bin/youtube-dl  However you can get it via brew if you want:
brew install youtube-dl  The basic process is the following:
youtube-dl [video URL]  By default that should download the highest quality format available (in case you didn&amp;rsquo;t know, youtube usually has multiple versions of a file for different qualities etc).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JSON undefined issues on IE8 and IE9</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2012/11/21/json-undefined-issues-on-ie8-and-ie9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2012 05:48:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2012/11/21/json-undefined-issues-on-ie8-and-ie9/</guid>
      <description>I had some issues today while testing in IE, where &amp;ldquo;JSON&amp;rdquo; was undefined. This was happening in IE8 and IE9, which is strange because the JSON functions are in those IE versions. The problem was IE&amp;rsquo;s compatibility view, which triggers rendering in sort-of-IE7 mode. Classy. This was making JSON undefined ;(
The usual fix for this is to add a meta tag to force IE to use &amp;ldquo;edge&amp;rdquo; (or a specific version if you like):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generating a powerset in ColdFusion</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2012/10/04/generating-a-powerset-in-coldfusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2012 11:20:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2012/10/04/generating-a-powerset-in-coldfusion/</guid>
      <description>I recently needed to generate a powerset (a set of all subsets) of 3 HTML select boxes. The idea was that a user could choose 1-many options from each box, and they had to choose a value from all 3 boxes (none could be empty).
Select #1 had 4 values
Select #2 had 7 values
Select #3 had 13 values
Now, I needed to generate every possible permutation for these 3 select boxes based on the rules I defined above.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modifying FW/1 variables.framework properties</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2012/09/30/modifying-fw1-variables-framework-properties/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2012 06:54:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2012/09/30/modifying-fw1-variables-framework-properties/</guid>
      <description>FW/1 gives you a nice, clean way to manage framework configuration properties. They&amp;rsquo;re all wrapped up inside Application.cfc in a structure called variables.framework, you can read more about them here under Configuring FW/1 Applications.
Our applications often have a need to use different values for these properties, depending on which environment the application is running in (development, testing, staging, production etc). An example of this might be reloadApplicationOnEveryRequest, which we want as true in development, but false elsewhere else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preventing FW/1 from reinitialising an app via the URL</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2012/09/27/preventing-fw1-from-reinitialising-an-app-via-the-url/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2012 12:57:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2012/09/27/preventing-fw1-from-reinitialising-an-app-via-the-url/</guid>
      <description>One of the things that FW/1 allows you to do is configure a reload &amp;ldquo;key&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;password&amp;rdquo; which you can use to reinit your application via URL.
So inside your Application.cfc you might have:
variables.framework = { reload = &#39;reinit&#39;, password = &amp;quot;mysecretkey&amp;quot; … }  So you can reinit your application (flush the application scope by re-running onApplicationStart()) by calling something like:
http://www.example.com/?reinit=mysecretkey  The &amp;ldquo;reload&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;password&amp;rdquo; properties can be changed to whatever you want for securities sake.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding a mail server to a Railo instance</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2012/09/26/adding-a-mail-server-to-a-railo-instance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2012/09/26/adding-a-mail-server-to-a-railo-instance/</guid>
      <description>We turn off all GUI based administration consoles in our production environments, this includes Railo&amp;rsquo;s admin area.
If you need to configure your Railo instance to include an SMTP server, you can add a line in WEB-INF/railo/railo-web.xml.cfm
Open up that file (probably as sudo), look for the  tag (which is empty by default) and insert the following:
&amp;lt;server port=&amp;quot;25&amp;quot; smtp=&amp;quot;127.0.0.1&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;  The &amp;ldquo;smtp&amp;rdquo; attribute should be the IP address of your SMTP server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing new fonts on Ubuntu server</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2012/09/24/installing-new-fonts-on-ubuntu-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2012 03:41:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2012/09/24/installing-new-fonts-on-ubuntu-server/</guid>
      <description>I had some new fonts to install on our test server that runs Ubuntu server. Pretty simple really, just noting it down here for next time:
 Upload/ssh the font(s) to your home folder on the server
 Copy font to the system fonts folder, this way it can be used by all users on the system sudo cp -R ~/trade-gothic /usr/share/fonts/truetype/
 Check permissions sudo chmod 755 /usr/share/fonts/truetype/trade-gothic/ Install the fonts so applications can use them sudo fc-cache -f -v  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whitespace issues in cfscript based functions</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2012/09/20/whitespace-issues-in-cfscript-based-functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2012 07:28:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2012/09/20/whitespace-issues-in-cfscript-based-functions/</guid>
      <description>Ok now we all know that ColdFusion is kind of lame when it comes to whitespace management, unless you specifically have &amp;ldquo;whitespace management&amp;rdquo; turned on for your server.
I have a function that is used to build the href value of a hyperlink. Nothing special there. However when I viewed the source of the page I was a little surprised to see a mountain of whitespace coming back from the function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jQuery UI dialog focus on first tabable element</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2012/09/14/jquery-ui-dialog-focus-on-first-tabable-element/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2012 06:27:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2012/09/14/jquery-ui-dialog-focus-on-first-tabable-element/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been using the jQuery UI dialog for a project recently, one thing that bugged me though, was that upon opening a dialog the first tabable element always gets focussed. This can be:
 hyperlinks input boxes select boxes buttons textareas etc  An example of this is:
A quick way around this is to fire a blur() method, targeting the first tabable element type of your dialog. So if I open up a dialog window with an id of dialog, I can do:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Timing synchronous JavaScript operations</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2012/08/13/timing-synchronous-javascript-operations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2012/08/13/timing-synchronous-javascript-operations/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s a cool little method on the console object that allows you to track how long an operation took to run. It&amp;rsquo;s called console.time.
Basically you just start a timer at the top of the code you want to time, like so:
console.time(&#39;timer-name&#39;); // your javascript goes here console.timeEnd(&#39;timer-name&#39;);  Each timer block should have a unique name (in the example above I called my timer &amp;lsquo;timer-name&amp;rsquo;), and you can have up to 10,000 timers running on a single page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting font MIME types in apache</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2012/08/09/setting-font-mime-types-in-apache/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2012/08/09/setting-font-mime-types-in-apache/</guid>
      <description>If your website is using custom fonts, you may see this line in your Chrome console:
 Resource interpreted as Font but transferred with MIME type application/octet-stream
 This is really kinda annoying, if you want to get rid of that warning then add the following directives to your apache conf/.htaccess:
AddType application/vnd.ms-fontobject eot AddType font/opentype otf AddType font/truetype ttf AddType application/x-font-woff .woff  See here for more information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turning off sessions for non-https traffic</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2012/08/06/turning-off-sessions-for-non-https-traffic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2012 07:05:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2012/08/06/turning-off-sessions-for-non-https-traffic/</guid>
      <description>Today I wanted to configure an application to only set secure cookies. Those are cookies that are only sent back to the server if over a secure (https) connection.
The main reason for this is to prevent session hijacking, where a bad guy might sniff the cookie values which links a user to the session &amp;ldquo;state&amp;rdquo; on the server. If they managed to do that, (which they could if the session was started on an http:// connection, then if/when the user logged on and was transferred to https://) the bad guy would still have their cookie values and thus would be able to visit the website as the logged in user.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Editing svn:ignore on the terminal</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2012/07/10/editing-svnignore-on-the-terminal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2012 12:49:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2012/07/10/editing-svnignore-on-the-terminal/</guid>
      <description>svn:ignore is a great way to exclude certain files or folders from being added to your subversion repository. Typically I&amp;rsquo;ll manage this via an IDE plugin like subclipse (in Eclipse), but if you want to do it via the terminal instead (bash)&amp;hellip;here&amp;rsquo;s how.
Crappy way You can add single values to your svn:ignore by running this command either at the root of your project or wherever directory you want the ignore to take effect:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Concatenating values into a single column with MySQL group_concat</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2012/07/05/concatenating-values-into-a-single-column-with-mysql-group_concat/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2012/07/05/concatenating-values-into-a-single-column-with-mysql-group_concat/</guid>
      <description>How many times have you wanted to return a list of grouped values from a database, in a single column, per row of your recordset? Actually I&amp;rsquo;ve wanted to do that a few times! Most of the time I&amp;rsquo;ll let the application layer handle that, but sometimes letting the database do the hard work fits the bill.
My not-so-theoretical example is course subjects (think English, Maths etc) that have 1-n &amp;ldquo;stages&amp;rdquo; (think categories) attached to them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jQuery tinyMCE issue with $.attr();</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2012/07/04/jquery-tinymce-issue-with-attr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2012/07/04/jquery-tinymce-issue-with-attr/</guid>
      <description>I had some strange behaviour with the jQuery verion of tinyMCE (3.4.6). Basically I was integrating the chosen library (which is build as a jQuery plugin), but it seems the $.attr(&amp;lsquo;id&amp;rsquo;) from within chosen.js was returning a JavaScript element reference instead of the value of the &amp;ldquo;id&amp;rdquo; field.

Some basic tracing showed the strange error:

The solution for me was moving to tinyMCE 3.5.4.1 (and jQuery 1.7.2, previously I was on 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache permission denied on Mac OSX Lion</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2012/06/05/apache-permission-denied-on-mac-osx-lion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2012/06/05/apache-permission-denied-on-mac-osx-lion/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve just upgraded to OSX Lion and had some trouble getting Apache to load a vhost. I kept getting a 403 permission denied error, but all my vhosts had the correct permission directives set.
Now by default your webserver document root is located in /Library/WebServer/Documents. I don&amp;rsquo;t really like that for my local machine, I&amp;rsquo;d rather store web files under my user account. Just tends to make things easier.
However&amp;hellip;if you&amp;rsquo;re getting a 403 error, and something like this in your apache error log (/var/log/apache2/error_log):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strange linefeed characters appearing on Mac</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2012/05/24/strange-linefeed-characters-appearing-on-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2012 04:14:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2012/05/24/strange-linefeed-characters-appearing-on-mac/</guid>
      <description>Had a funny situation today where I was emailed a bash program file, but simply downloading the attachment from gmail (in Chrome) added a linefeed (\r) to the file.
This is strange because I never actually opened the file to edit, so I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what was writing those chars to the file. I&amp;rsquo;m on a Mac (OSX 10.6.8), so I get the line feed character in general, but just not in this case as the file was never opened.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Find and Replace with line breaks in Eclipse</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2012/03/17/find-and-replace-with-line-breaks-in-eclipse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2012 02:56:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2012/03/17/find-and-replace-with-line-breaks-in-eclipse/</guid>
      <description>Often with doing a find and replace you want to use line breaks in the find (or replace) criteria. Sometimes I&amp;rsquo;ll have a column of data from a csv that I want to modify&amp;hellip;whatever.
You can now check the &amp;ldquo;regular expressions&amp;rdquo; checkbox while doing a file search in Eclipse and specify &amp;ldquo;\R&amp;rdquo; to find or replace line breaks (platform independent).
Eg replace line breaks with commas:
Other interesting and useful options are:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Error restoring MySQL database when USING BTREE on indexes</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2012/03/15/error-restoring-mysql-database-when-using-btree-on-indexes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2012 04:42:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2012/03/15/error-restoring-mysql-database-when-using-btree-on-indexes/</guid>
      <description>Occasionally when I&amp;rsquo;m restoring a database that was backed up from a different server than the one I&amp;rsquo;m restoring on I get an error along the lines of:
&amp;gt;[Error] Script lines: 5-17 ------------------------- You have an error in your SQL syntax; check the manual that corresponds to your MySQL server version for the right syntax to use near &#39;USING BTREE ) ENGINE=InnoDB DEFAULT CHARSET=utf8&#39; at line 11 Warnings: ---&amp;gt; W (1): You have an error in your SQL syntax; check the manual that corresponds to your MySQL server version for the right syntax to use near &#39;USING BTREE ) ENGINE=InnoDB DEFAULT CHARSET=utf8&#39; at line 11  Hmm, the docs suggest that BTREE is a valid index type for both MyISAM and InnoDB.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turning voice over off permanently on Max OSX</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2012/03/14/turning-voice-over-off-permanently-on-max-osx/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2012 05:41:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2012/03/14/turning-voice-over-off-permanently-on-max-osx/</guid>
      <description>One of the keyboard shortcuts I often use is command-F6, but I seem to accidentally hit command-F5 on most occasions :(
Problem with this is that the god awful &amp;ldquo;voice over&amp;rdquo; starts yapping away. Well if you&amp;rsquo;re like me and know that you&amp;rsquo;ll pretty much never want this enabled (at least for now!) then here&amp;rsquo;s how you turn it off permanently.
 Open up system preferences Click on keyboard Go to the keyboard shortcuts tab Choose universal access from the list on the left Uncheck the &amp;ldquo;Turn voice over on or off&amp;rdquo; checkbox  Breathe a sigh of relief :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitter bootstrap - modal not working in firefox</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2011/10/27/twitter-bootstrap-modal-not-working-in-firefox/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2011 07:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2011/10/27/twitter-bootstrap-modal-not-working-in-firefox/</guid>
      <description>Quick heads up for those having issues getting the modal window in the twitter bootstrap to work in firefox, I had a problem where the overlay would show but not the actual modal window content. Seems there is a problem if you&amp;rsquo;re using animation (fade etc).
See here for more information.
For now we use no animation, so a typical modal source example might be (note: no animation as is the default in the docs):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FarCry Plugin - Webtop Tools</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2011/08/17/farcry-plugin-webtop-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2011 00:38:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2011/08/17/farcry-plugin-webtop-tools/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re starting to compile a list of internal tools used when developing a FarCry application. I thought it might be simpler to create a small FarCry plugin to keep them all in the same place, makes it easier to use across multiple projects.
The plugin currently contains 2 scripts:
 FarCry database diff (MySQL only at this stage) Content Object Meta  The database diff looks for case-sensitivity differences between your ColdFusion components and the actual MySQL table names (MySQL only).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customising search results from google cse</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2011/08/17/customising-search-results-from-google-cse/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2011/08/17/customising-search-results-from-google-cse/</guid>
      <description>Google custom search engine (cse) is pretty cool, in fact it&amp;rsquo;s very cool. Within minutes you can have the ability to search your entire site all with a snippet of code! And for a nominal fee you can deliver these results without ads :)
We use google cse for most of our sites but the other day we ran into a slight problem. The site in question has both public and private access, the public site is delivered over http and has plenty of indexable content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Label vs Title in FarCry</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2011/07/31/label-vs-title-in-farcry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2011 23:16:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2011/07/31/label-vs-title-in-farcry/</guid>
      <description>All system content objects (and those custom types which extend &amp;ldquo;types&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;versions&amp;rdquo; etc) in FarCry have the &amp;ldquo;label&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;title&amp;rdquo; properties. Most of the time the value of these are identical, I find myself typically using the &amp;ldquo;title&amp;rdquo; property in formtools as well as any display methods. The question of course is why have both these if they&amp;rsquo;re always exactly the same?
A note on the FarCry forums suggested that this was a handy way split what you might want to use in a display method vs an admin screen or any other scenario etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FarCry Tip - Enable cfc&#39;s in your Railo ProxyPassMatch</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2011/07/01/farcry-tip-enable-cfcs-in-your-railo-proxypassmatch/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 04:04:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2011/07/01/farcry-tip-enable-cfcs-in-your-railo-proxypassmatch/</guid>
      <description>I ran into an issue today while working on a FarCry project, basically when I opened up the &amp;ldquo;Related Content&amp;rdquo; popup from the WYSIWYG editor it was blank. Nothing. Not the usual tabs for Images, File, Flash etc.
The Railo logs were empty but Apache was throwing a strange error which I hadn&amp;rsquo;t seen before: &amp;ldquo;Couldn&amp;rsquo;t initialize from remote server, JRun server(s) probably down.&amp;rdquo;. Funny as I&amp;rsquo;m not even using JRun!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FarCry - grouping formtool category items</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2011/07/01/farcry-grouping-formtool-category-items/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:51:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2011/07/01/farcry-grouping-formtool-category-items/</guid>
      <description>A new project we&amp;rsquo;re working has the need to categorise each new content object, for this we use the built in FarCry category/keyword formtool.
By default the render type is a multi-select tree, I wanted a single select dropdown. Luckily formtools makes this oh so simple.
&amp;lt;cfproperty name=&amp;quot;catHTML&amp;quot; type=&amp;quot;nstring&amp;quot; required=&amp;quot;true&amp;quot; default=&amp;quot;&amp;quot; ftSeq=&amp;quot;2&amp;quot; ftwizardStep=&amp;quot;Content&amp;quot; ftValidation=&amp;quot;required&amp;quot; ftFieldset=&amp;quot;General Details&amp;quot; ftLabel=&amp;quot;Categories&amp;quot; ftType=&amp;quot;Category&amp;quot; ftAlias=&amp;quot;sections&amp;quot; ftRenderType=&amp;quot;dropdown&amp;quot; ftSelectSize=&amp;quot;1&amp;quot; ftSelectMultiple=&amp;quot;false&amp;quot; ftAliasAsOptGroup=&amp;quot;true&amp;quot;&amp;gt;  Note that I&amp;rsquo;ve set the dropdown size to 1 and multiple select to false.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FarCry Tip - remove install directory</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2011/06/30/farcry-tip-remove-install-directory/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2011 00:39:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2011/06/30/farcry-tip-remove-install-directory/</guid>
      <description>After you install FarCry you must make sure to delete the &amp;ldquo;install&amp;rdquo; folder(s) that FarCry leaves behind. Otherwise it&amp;rsquo;s possible for anyone to access the installer wizard again from your production website, and as it&amp;rsquo;s the installer they don&amp;rsquo;t even need to be logged in to cause real havoc. Not good.
By default, as of FarCry 6.1.x, there are 2 install folders to delete:
 farcry.core.webtop.install farcry.plugins.farcrycms.install  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mura - overriding dspCrumblistLinks</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2011/05/31/mura-overriding-dspcrumblistlinks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2011/05/31/mura-overriding-dspcrumblistlinks/</guid>
      <description>Like most CMS solutions out there, Mura CMS gives you some cool hooks to override core functionality. See the developer guides for more information.
I&amp;rsquo;ve created a repository on github to store any customisations or extensions that could be cherry picked for use in any Mura app.
First up was a super simple one for breadcrumbs. By default, Mura will put an &amp;ldquo;a href&amp;rdquo; around the last item in the crumb list.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FarCry to Mura - migrating data from FarCry to Mura CMS</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2011/05/29/farcry-to-mura-migrating-data-from-farcry-to-mura-cms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2011/05/29/farcry-to-mura-migrating-data-from-farcry-to-mura-cms/</guid>
      <description>For years here at Learnosity we&amp;rsquo;ve been using FarCry for most of our CMS requirements (yes, I know that FarCry, or rather farcrycms, is a lot more than just a CMS).
For one reason or another we decided it was time to look at some of the other options for content management in the ColdFusion sphere, Mura CMS was a likely candidate for evalutation.
We had a small-ish site that was already running in FarCry 6+ which we wanted to port to Mura so we could really get a feel for how things worked in Mura-land.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wordpress - detecting the categories of a post</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2011/05/11/wordpress-detecting-the-categories-of-a-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2011 13:48:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2011/05/11/wordpress-detecting-the-categories-of-a-post/</guid>
      <description>I was creating a Wordpress child theme (the best way to modify/override your themes) tonight and had the need to have different display options depending on which categories the blog article had. So for example if I had a post categorised with &amp;ldquo;portfolio&amp;rdquo;, I wanted to hide the comments form which usually sits at the bottom of a post.
The following snippet will loop over all post categories, if it finds that &amp;ldquo;portfolio&amp;rdquo; is one of the categories assigned to the current post then a local variable (boolean) is set which you can use to hide Wordpress functions anywhere in the current template.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FancyBox for Wordpress plugin not working</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2011/05/11/fancybox-for-wordpress-plugin-not-working/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2011 13:42:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2011/05/11/fancybox-for-wordpress-plugin-not-working/</guid>
      <description>I just spent some time figuring out why fancybox wasn&amp;rsquo;t working tonight (image thumbnails were just linking to the large image&amp;hellip;not loading the overlay as they should). It now seems obvious after the fact but as far as I can see it&amp;rsquo;s NOT in the fancybox docs.
When you insert your gallery from the media section of a page in wp-admin, you HAVE to choose &amp;ldquo;Image File&amp;rdquo;, not &amp;ldquo;Attachment Page&amp;rdquo;. That&amp;rsquo;s it!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FarCry twitter plugin</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2011/04/17/farcry-twitter-plugin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2011 12:04:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2011/04/17/farcry-twitter-plugin/</guid>
      <description>I spent a couple of hours on a FarCry plugin for twitter yesterday based off their official API.
What? This plugin basically wraps up the options that the offical twitter API gives you including:
 Twitter username Showing avatars, timestamps, hashtags etc Theme appearance (colours for background and text etc Dimensions of widget  For more, visit the project page, download it and have a play.
Why? Although the twitter API is super simple to implement, it&amp;rsquo;s always handy to have things wrapped up as a plugin so we can easily create as many widgets as we need and handle caching etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MySQL alternative to MSSQL&#39;&#39;s isNull()</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2011/03/03/mysql-alternative-to-mssqls-isnull/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2011/03/03/mysql-alternative-to-mssqls-isnull/</guid>
      <description>I was looking for a way to do isNull() in MySQL the other day, for those that don&amp;rsquo;t know this means you can do something like:
SELECT isNull(mycolumn, &#39;blah&#39;) FROM myTable;  If the value in mycolumn is NULL, then &amp;lsquo;blah&amp;rsquo; is returned, this can of course be any string literal/numeric value you want. MySQL doesn&amp;rsquo;t have isNull() but it does have ifNull() which is basically the same.
SELECT ifNull(mycolumn, &#39;blah&#39;) FROM myTable;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL for finding duplicate values</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2011/02/08/sql-for-finding-duplicate-values/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2011 06:47:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2011/02/08/sql-for-finding-duplicate-values/</guid>
      <description>Quick post to remind me how to check a table column for duplicate values next time I&amp;rsquo;m looking for it (when my memory fails!)
SELECT id, count(id) FROM mytable GROUP BY id HAVING count(id) &amp;gt; 1  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Checking for correct case-sensitive tables in FarCry</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2011/01/12/checking-for-correct-case-sensitive-tables-in-farcry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2011 22:47:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2011/01/12/checking-for-correct-case-sensitive-tables-in-farcry/</guid>
      <description>We run several FarCry projects at Learnosity and all of them run on Linux. We have occasionally come across issues where the FarCry codebase will refer to a MySQL table in the wrong &amp;ldquo;case&amp;rdquo;.
E.g. referring to &amp;ldquo;dmhtml&amp;rdquo; where the actual table name is &amp;ldquo;dmHTML&amp;rdquo;.
This is course fails in any case sensitive environment. Note that we also run our Macs as case sensitive in development to help find these issues before deploying to a stage/production server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding Prototype methods to jQuery</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2010/12/07/adding-prototype-methods-to-jquery/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2010/12/07/adding-prototype-methods-to-jquery/</guid>
      <description>We recently upgraded a project which was using the Prototype JavaScript framework to use jQuery and ran into a few methods which didn&amp;rsquo;t exist in jQuery at all.
A quick search gave us an easy solution; by adding a prototype property (not related to the Prototype framework) to String.prototype we can give every string in our codebase access to these methods as if they were part of the JavaScript spec (or the jQuery library).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Importing a csv into MySQL using the command line</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2010/11/14/importing-a-csv-into-mysql-using-the-command-line/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2010 23:38:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2010/11/14/importing-a-csv-into-mysql-using-the-command-line/</guid>
      <description>UPDATE 16th Nov 2010: I had some issues with the import which I noted in the first code example below
Today I had to import csv into a single mysql table. The destination table only had 5 columns and the csv was around 22MB (around 400,000 records). The csv also contained more columns that I needed for the import. Sometimes I&amp;rsquo;ll use a GUI to do this as I usually have one open, but it never ceases to amaze me how much slower GUI tools are compared to the command line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Case sensitive development on Mac OS X</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2010/10/04/case-sensitive-development-on-mac-os-x/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2010/10/04/case-sensitive-development-on-mac-os-x/</guid>
      <description>At work most of the developers are on Mac OS X but our staging and production environments are Linux based. This means development is case insensitive but stage/production is case sensitive. Although we have development guidelines/standards which dictate file and database naming conventions etc, human error can still occur (in terms of referencing files with a different &amp;ldquo;case&amp;rdquo;). We also use a few open source packages where we obviously don&amp;rsquo;t have control over the naming of files or the references to database tables within those files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tip when adding &#34;allowMultiQueries=true&#34; to your MySQL DSN in ColdFusion</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2010/09/08/tip-when-adding-allowmultiqueriestrue-to-your-mysql-dsn-in-coldfusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2010/09/08/tip-when-adding-allowmultiqueriestrue-to-your-mysql-dsn-in-coldfusion/</guid>
      <description>Scenario&amp;hellip;I&amp;rsquo;m using ColdFusion 9 and MySQL 5. I already had my DSN setup but had a requirement to get the last inserted id from a MySQL INSERT statement (I&amp;rsquo;m using auto-incrementing integer&amp;rsquo;s).
As most people know, the best way to do this (in MySQL) is using the last_insert_id() function. I wanted to attach this to the end of my INSERT statement for performance reasons, as I&amp;rsquo;d only be sending one query to the server instead of separate ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CFML issue on Railo with the accelerate cache tag</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2010/05/27/cfml-issue-on-railo-with-the-accelerate-cache-tag/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2010 06:30:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2010/05/27/cfml-issue-on-railo-with-the-accelerate-cache-tag/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve been using Brandon Purcell&amp;rsquo;s excellent accelerate custom cache tag for a few projects. I had an issue today while testing a new app which is about to go live. It seemed that whatever I did nothing would be cached.
Upon investigation it seemed that the caching worked fine on Adobe ColdFusion but not on Railo. A quick look at the codebase brought me to this line:
&amp;lt;cfif IsDefined(&amp;quot;application.accelerator.#scriptName#.#primarykey#.#secondaryKey#&amp;quot;)  Basically this was always returning false, even when I knew the key was in the application scope.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Removing duplicate rows in Open Office (calc)</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2010/05/13/removing-duplicate-rows-in-open-office-calc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2010 05:05:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2010/05/13/removing-duplicate-rows-in-open-office-calc/</guid>
      <description>I needed to de-dupe a spreadsheet the other day and found a great how-to from google. Thought I&amp;rsquo;d post it here for my own future purposes:
There is no automatic function to remove duplicate rows. Follow these steps to delete all rows that have duplicate values in column A:
 Select all cells of the current data range.
On most systems, you can click any cell inside the data range, then press Ctrl+Multiplication key on the numeric keypad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IE and underscores in domain names</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2010/05/09/ie-and-underscores-in-domain-names/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2010 23:09:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2010/05/09/ie-and-underscores-in-domain-names/</guid>
      <description>Ok, a short warning to those who use underscores in their domain names. Underscores you say? Aren&amp;rsquo;t they illegal characters in domain names? Why yes they are (but I think they&amp;rsquo;re valid in sub-domains&amp;hellip;not sure), but you may find yourself using them in development environments, particularly if you&amp;rsquo;re doing a re-design. Think something like _http://mysite_v2.local/_ etc
Now, this works of course and everything is fine and dandy because your using your own hosts file to make it &amp;ldquo;legal&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip;except that Internet Explorer has this little quirk where it doesn&amp;rsquo;t persist your session (cookie) information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Support Details - tech support management</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2010/04/22/support-details-tech-support-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2010 06:52:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2010/04/22/support-details-tech-support-management/</guid>
      <description>Ever dealt with a client where you wanted to know their operating environment? Thinks like what operating system they are running (and version), which browser type and version, whether they have JavaScript enabled etc? Sounds easy but for some clients this is like being asked to provide a detailed analysis of early 7th century rock formations around Stone Henge&amp;hellip;in Latin. :(
Here&amp;rsquo;s a super simple solution that anyone could use :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detecting https across Railo and ColdFusion Server</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2010/03/03/detecting-https-across-railo-and-coldfusion-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2010 03:14:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2010/03/03/detecting-https-across-railo-and-coldfusion-server/</guid>
      <description>Previously I had a way of detecting whether page requests were being made via ssl but today I came across a scenario where this doesn&amp;rsquo;t work. Let me explain&amp;hellip;
Right now we&amp;rsquo;re looking at developing across different ColdFusion engines, &amp;ldquo;ColdFusion&amp;rdquo; of course but also &amp;ldquo;Railo&amp;rdquo;. One of the applications we had detected whether a request was being made securely (https) and if it wasn&amp;rsquo;t we turned off session management for security reasons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cfhttp issues using &#34;.local&#34; on Max OSX</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2010/01/19/cfhttp-issues-using-local-on-max-osx/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2010 23:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2010/01/19/cfhttp-issues-using-local-on-max-osx/</guid>
      <description>Ran into an interesting problem today doing something quite simple. Basically all I was doing was posting xml data to a URL, but I kept getting a 408 request timeout and I didn&amp;rsquo;t know why.
We happen to use the &amp;ldquo;.local&amp;rdquo; domain name structure for local development. I was posting data from one local site to another e.g.
http://mysite1.local -&amp;gt; http://mysite2.local
When I dumped cfhttp on the posting page I got the following error:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BrowserLab live on adobe.com</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2009/10/30/browserlab-live-on-adobe-com/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2009 01:02:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2009/10/30/browserlab-live-on-adobe-com/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m probably a bit behind the times with this one, but Adobe have added &amp;ldquo;BrowserLab&amp;rdquo; functionality to &amp;ldquo;preview and test your web pages on leading browsers and operating systems - on demand&amp;rdquo;.
Seems to work like other paid services, but is free :)
https://browserlab.adobe.com/
Available browser options (across mac and windows) include:
 IE 6/7/8 Firefox 2&amp;frasl;3 Safari 3&amp;frasl;4</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extracting URL variables using JavaScript</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2009/10/28/extracting-url-variables-using-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2009 00:40:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2009/10/28/extracting-url-variables-using-javascript/</guid>
      <description>Server side languages are cool in that they give you a nice associative array to access URL variables. ColdFusion has the URL scope, PHP has $_GET[] etc, but how do you get these values easily with JavaScript?
I came across a post over at Jake Munson&amp;rsquo;s blog which had just what I needed. Actually although Jakes solution was perfectly valid, I preferred a slight modification from one of the commenters which wrapped the entire URL string into an associative array so you can access the entire URL scope, as well as extracting a specific value via a key.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Firefox changing default download location?</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2009/08/15/firefox-changing-default-download-location/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2009 08:04:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2009/08/15/firefox-changing-default-download-location/</guid>
      <description>Hmm it seems firefox (Windows) 3.5.2 has decided to change the default location for downloading files. Used to be the desktop, but if you suddenly discover that you can&amp;rsquo;t find things you&amp;rsquo;ve download you might want to head to Tools-&amp;gt;Options in firefox.
If you see &amp;ldquo;Downloads&amp;rdquo; as the chosen folder (as below), you can change it back to the desktop.
Safari (at least on the Mac) also annoyingly places files there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New location for FarCry subversion repositories</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2009/08/15/new-location-for-farcry-subversion-repositories/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2009 07:21:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2009/08/15/new-location-for-farcry-subversion-repositories/</guid>
      <description>The folks at Daemon have completed some migrations with their subversion repositories which directly effects FarCry. Notes from the farcry-dev groups:
All URL&amp;rsquo;s should be replaced with this repo location: https://modius.svn.cvsdude.com/farcry
All project folders are relative to this root. For example, the p520 branch for FarCry 5.2.x is available here: https://modius.svn.cvsdude.com/farcry/core/branches/p520/
You can re-checkout or use the &amp;ldquo;relocate&amp;rdquo; command if your SVN client supports.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hiding the FarCry tray on the front end</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2009/07/14/hiding-the-farcry-tray-on-the-front-end/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2009 04:42:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2009/07/14/hiding-the-farcry-tray-on-the-front-end/</guid>
      <description>Came across this nice tip a little while ago from AJ Mercer on the farcry-dev group.
It hides the FarCry &amp;ldquo;tray&amp;rdquo; which is visible on the front end of your website to users who are logged in to FarCry. I happen to have a use case for this at the moment so it was good timing.
Simply put this code snippet in any template there you don&amp;rsquo;t want the tray appearing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prototype/scriptaculous issue with Sortable.create()</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2009/06/15/prototypescriptaculous-issue-with-sortablecreate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2009 05:33:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2009/06/15/prototypescriptaculous-issue-with-sortablecreate/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing some custom sorting within FarCry using the prototype/scriptaculous libraries as they already exist in the FarCry framework by default.
I was having trouble getting the Sortable.create() to work properly and the main docs site for scriptaculous seems severely lacking in examples. Basically the &amp;ldquo;sorting&amp;rdquo; action was happening fine but no event was being fired &amp;ldquo;onUpdate&amp;rdquo;. No exception was being thrown, just that nothing was happening after the drag/drop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting application variables in FarCry</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2009/06/09/setting-application-variables-in-farcry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2009 01:59:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2009/06/09/setting-application-variables-in-farcry/</guid>
      <description>I just thought I&amp;rsquo;d write up some quick thoughts on setting application scoped variables in FarCry as it occured to me that it could be a little confusing to non-FarCry developers.
It doesn&amp;rsquo;t really matter which framework you use, you can theoretically set you application variables anywhere you want, but ideally you want to follow some sort of methodology and consistency both with the rest of your development team and of course the framework you happen to be using.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting the sort order for custom admin items in FarCry</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2009/05/29/setting-the-sort-order-for-custom-admin-items/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2009 00:56:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2009/05/29/setting-the-sort-order-for-custom-admin-items/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve wanted to be able to control the sort order of menu and menuitems in the customadmin.xml (or equivalent) file for quite a while but hadn&amp;rsquo;t found how to do it. Only today did I find the ability, I believe it&amp;rsquo;s a FarCry 5+ feature which was why I didn&amp;rsquo;t see it before.
The answer is simple, just add a &amp;ldquo;sequence&amp;rdquo; attribute to your menu or menuitem tag:
&amp;lt;menu mergeType=&amp;quot;merge&amp;quot; sequence=&amp;quot;1&amp;quot; id=&amp;quot;farcry_studentsonlineadminSubSection&amp;quot; label=&amp;quot;Homepage Content&amp;quot; labelType=&amp;quot;value&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;menuitem id=&amp;quot;boardlinks&amp;quot; sequence=&amp;quot;1&amp;quot; label=&amp;quot;Board Links&amp;quot; link=&amp;quot;/admin/customadmin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing the sort order of FarCry categories/keywords</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2009/05/28/changing-the-sort-order-of-farcry-categorieskeywords/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2009 23:23:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2009/05/28/changing-the-sort-order-of-farcry-categorieskeywords/</guid>
      <description>Categorising content with keywords (or &amp;ldquo;tags&amp;rdquo;) is a well known concept these days and it&amp;rsquo;s good to know that FarCry has had this ability long before it became cool!
I&amp;rsquo;m using categories to group content for a custom type but I needed to allow the editors to sort these categories and not rely on the alphabetical order of the category etc.
Luckily in FarCry categories use the nested tree object model (exactly like the navigation tree) so sorting is absolutely possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting a &#34;Label&#34; property tip for FarCry 5</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2009/05/28/setting-a-label-property-tip-for-farcry-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2009 02:26:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2009/05/28/setting-a-label-property-tip-for-farcry-5/</guid>
      <description>Quick tip which might fix some problems for people as it did for me today.
I had a custom object for a calendar where the main title was &amp;ldquo;EventTitle&amp;rdquo;. Now as you may know FarCry uses the &amp;ldquo;label&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;title&amp;rdquo; property from types.cfc by default.
As I wasn&amp;rsquo;t using this default property my label value was &amp;ldquo;incomplete&amp;rdquo; in the database. This didn&amp;rsquo;t really bother me as it would never be seen, however it was preventing my content object from being approved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Development configuration tips for Ubuntu</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/12/13/development-configuration-tips-for-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2008 02:28:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/12/13/development-configuration-tips-for-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>I just setup my machine at home with Ubuntu 8.10 (desktop) which was so easy think I saved hours off the time it would normally take with Windows. So much is already installed and ready to go and with apt (or the Synaptic package manager) it&amp;rsquo;s super quick to download and install extra things things like MySQL, PHP, Apache, Java etc
Here are some notes which helped me out when configuring some of these development tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to do a case-sensitive test of your codebase</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/12/04/how-to-do-a-case-sensitive-test-of-your-codebase/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2008 23:26:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/12/04/how-to-do-a-case-sensitive-test-of-your-codebase/</guid>
      <description>Cross platform development and/or hosting makes for interesting times. Making sure that your entire codebase and configuration are compatible and work in different operating environments is obviously paramount to a successful project, particularly if you are &amp;ldquo;releasing&amp;rdquo; a product to the public either open source or commercially.
At Lynch Consulting all of our production servers are Linux based but the development team spreads across Linux, Mac and the occasional Windows machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Querying multiple databases within one cfquery</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/12/03/querying-multiple-databases-within-one-cfquery/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/12/03/querying-multiple-databases-within-one-cfquery/</guid>
      <description>In discussing a possible caching solution at work a suggestion was made to use a secondary database (on the same server) to store some key application data. It&amp;rsquo;s not really important to describe why we wanted to do this, suffice to say that my concern was if and when the application would need to perform a SQL &amp;ldquo;JOIN&amp;rdquo; between the primary and secondary (caching) database as I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure if it was technically possible within our environment (ColdFusion 8, MySQL).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing a new FarCry 5 project - (Extended) Advanced Mode</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/11/28/installing-a-new-farcry-5-project-extended-advanced-mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2008 04:07:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/11/28/installing-a-new-farcry-5-project-extended-advanced-mode/</guid>
      <description>There are several installation options for the latest version of FarCry (5.0.2) which makes things nice and flexible for the framework to be used by different people in a variety of setups.
The deployment configurations page has some easy to follow instructions for installing in &amp;ldquo;Standalone&amp;rdquo; mode. This is really the best option if you are in a shared environment where you may not have control over ColdFusion mappings, but also if you are looking to get up and running quickly (maybe you just want to evaluate the product etc).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security reminder - Are you using scriptprotect?</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/11/25/security-reminder-are-you-using-scriptprotect/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2008 01:30:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/11/25/security-reminder-are-you-using-scriptprotect/</guid>
      <description>One of our applications had an entry in the ColdFusion exception logs today:
 ScriptProtect error replacing insecure tag in scope CGI;
 Essentially someone (via an automated process) was trying to find a weakness in our application by trying URL&amp;rsquo;s like:
http://www.mysite.com/?mode=&amp;gt;&#39;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;script&amp;gt;alert(40891)&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;  Luckily we use scriptprotect (among many other defensive techniques) to prevent this type of thing from causing any damage. But I just thought I&amp;rsquo;d throw out a quick reminder to EVERYONE using CF7+ (or Railo) to make sure and use the scriptprotect attribute of either the cfapplication tag or Application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use application.applicationName? Careful when re-initing your app</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/11/24/use-applicationapplicationname-careful-when-re-initing-your-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2008 10:54:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/11/24/use-applicationapplicationname-careful-when-re-initing-your-app/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m sure most ColdFusion developers know that the application scope has a built-in variable called application.applicationName which stores the name of the application that you specify in the cfapplication tag or the this.name value if your using Application.cfc. This doesn&amp;rsquo;t appear when you dump the application scope&amp;hellip;but it&amp;rsquo;s there.
Today I wanted to use this variable, everything was working fine until I ran into an error when I re-initialised my application via a URL variable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cfqueryparam does not work in ORDER BY, what are my options?</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/11/22/cfqueryparam-does-not-work-in-order-by-what-are-my-options/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2008 02:15:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/11/22/cfqueryparam-does-not-work-in-order-by-what-are-my-options/</guid>
      <description>For those that don&amp;rsquo;t know, ColdFusion&amp;rsquo;s cfqueryparam won&amp;rsquo;t work on a SQL ORDER BY clause, so the following will not work:
&amp;lt;cfquery name=&amp;quot;qGetUsers&amp;quot; datasource=&amp;quot;mydsn&amp;quot;&amp;gt; SELECT	FirstName, LastName FROM	Users ORDER BY &amp;lt;cfqueryparam cfsqltype=&amp;quot;cf_sql_varchar&amp;quot; value=&amp;quot;#arguments.order#&amp;quot; /&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/cfquery&amp;gt;  This is really nothing new, people have been talking about this for years but with the spate of recent SQL injection attacks (note that I meant to publish this around sept 08 but got sidetracked!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Logging all MySQL queries on Mac OSX</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/11/19/logging-all-mysql-queries-on-mac-osx/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/11/19/logging-all-mysql-queries-on-mac-osx/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve been doing some debugging of a 3rd party application recently where we had some possible performance concerns under a certain load and/or size of data in the database. What we wanted to know was exactly which queries (and how many) where hitting the database on a specific page request.
The simplest method was to turn on logging of all queries on the local MySQL database, this is turned off by default as like most debugging techniques it adds overhead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forgot to import your ColdFusion tag libraries?</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/11/15/forgot-to-import-your-coldfusion-tag-libraries/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2008 09:55:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/11/15/forgot-to-import-your-coldfusion-tag-libraries/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been bitten by the &amp;ldquo;forgetting to add &amp;rdquo; when importing ColdFusion custom tags before. If you also have then you know what I mean and have shared the frustration&amp;hellip;basically your custom tag does nothing but you get no error from ColdFusion, nada, zip! Depending on the scenario this can lead to some wasted hair pulling time!
The reason is of course that the syntax to import custom tags is perfectly valid XML which is ignored by ColdFusion server because you forgot to add  tag.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google releases video chat</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/11/12/google-releases-video-chat/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2008 03:04:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/11/12/google-releases-video-chat/</guid>
      <description>For those that use gtalk/gmail, google have finally caught up and released voice and video chat.
They even help you buy a webcam!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>var scoping - how and where do you set your function variables?</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/11/12/var-scoping-how-and-where-do-you-set-your-function-variables/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2008 00:40:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/11/12/var-scoping-how-and-where-do-you-set-your-function-variables/</guid>
      <description>As everybody knows you should var scope ALL local function variables inside ColdFusion components, and these variables must be declared at the top of your function before any other code. If you place other code above a &amp;ldquo;var&amp;rdquo; scoped variable in your method signature an exception will be thrown.
Depending on how you define you methods this will probably be fine, but I got to thinking recently on how this works with exception handling within your function, specifically for try/catch blocks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Invalid serial number&#34; when upgrading to Flex Builder 3 Pro</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/11/10/invalid-serial-number-when-upgrading-to-flex-builder-3-pro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2008 03:16:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/11/10/invalid-serial-number-when-upgrading-to-flex-builder-3-pro/</guid>
      <description>Ok this was annoying&amp;hellip;I had an older trial version of the standalone Flex Builder 3 on my system (Mac 10.5) and wanted to activate it with a new serial for FB3 Professional.
Whenever I entered the serial in &amp;ldquo;Help -&amp;gt; Manage Flex Licenses&amp;rdquo; I kept getting a message saying &amp;ldquo;Invalid serial number&amp;rdquo; even though it was a brand new serial. Damn.
Mark gave me the original hint to remove the license.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Caveat using dateDiff() to compare difference in days</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/11/03/caveat-using-datediff-to-compare-difference-in-days/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2008 06:34:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/11/03/caveat-using-datediff-to-compare-difference-in-days/</guid>
      <description>I had some problems a little while ago using dateCompare() and the same thing bit me recently with dateDiff(). Well really I had a problem with createODBCDate(), but let me explain.
I wanted to compare the &amp;ldquo;day&amp;rdquo; value between 2 dates like;
&amp;lt;cfscript&amp;gt; date1 = now(); date2 = myQuery.dateCreated; dateDifference = dateDiff(&amp;quot;d&amp;quot;, date1, date2);	&amp;lt;/cfscript&amp;gt;  The initial problem was that &amp;ldquo;myQuery.dateCreated&amp;rdquo; has a time value associated with it, as does the value of now().</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fun with reserved words in MySQL 5</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/10/27/fun-with-reserved-words-in-mysql-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/10/27/fun-with-reserved-words-in-mysql-5/</guid>
      <description>Most tools or languages you work with have words which are &amp;ldquo;reserved&amp;rdquo;, meaning you cannot use them in a variable declaration or schema definition etc as they have special treatment in the underlying system. If you try to do this you&amp;rsquo;ll usually get an immediate error.
Today I needed to change an existing SQL query from a &amp;ldquo;SELECT *&amp;rdquo; to explicitly defining each column because I wanted to add some date formating at the SQL level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aqua Data Studio 7 includes an ER modeler</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/10/22/aqua-data-studio-7-includes-an-er-modeler/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2008 03:23:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/10/22/aqua-data-studio-7-includes-an-er-modeler/</guid>
      <description>Those of you who miss diagramming support when using MySQL tools will be pleased to know that the latest version of Aqua Data Studio has support for ER Modeling :)
 The Entity-Relationship (ER) Modeler we’ve built into Aqua Data Studio 7 is as powerful as even the best standalone database diagramming tools. Use it to design a new database from scratch, understand and clean up a database nightmare in your office, or visually understand entity relationships in existing databases to write more effective SQL queries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Problems submitting a form via &#39;enter&#39; in IE</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/10/22/problems-submitting-a-form-via-enter-in-ie/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2008 02:35:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/10/22/problems-submitting-a-form-via-enter-in-ie/</guid>
      <description>Like many things, handling form submissions with ColdFusion can be done many many ways. A preferred method which I&amp;rsquo;ve been using for years now is looking for a specific element in the form struct. Something like:
&amp;lt;cfif structKeyExists(form, &amp;quot;myelement&amp;quot;)&amp;gt; &amp;lt;!--- handle form submission here ---&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/cfif&amp;gt;  Most times I use a hidden field as the form element to look for (in my structKeyExists()), but I came across something funny today where I happened to be looking for the name of a submit button.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>generateRandomKey() UDF with several handy options</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/10/13/generaterandomkey-udf-with-several-handy-options/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2008 13:29:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/10/13/generaterandomkey-udf-with-several-handy-options/</guid>
      <description>Working on a ColdFusion project recently I had the need to generate a random key; the format of which was based on a specific set of business rules. I actually ended up writing a basic UDF to handle this but after the fact I went looking to see if I could find something which provided some of the features I was after.
Although I found several through google and cflib they weren&amp;rsquo;t completely what I was after.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mooFlair on Adobe&#39;s top 10 list</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/09/03/mooflair-on-adobes-top-10-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2008 22:33:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/09/03/mooflair-on-adobes-top-10-list/</guid>
      <description>Areez Gangji has just posted on Adobe devnet an article listing the &amp;ldquo;Top 10 Adobe Flex and AIR applications for students&amp;rdquo;.
I&amp;rsquo;m very proud to say that a good friend (and fellow Daemon alumni) Patrick Tai has an app on their called mooFlair which he originally built for the AIR derby.
What is mooFlair?
 A desktop application that helps you to manage and watch both online and offline FLVs videos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome - Google entering the browser market</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/09/02/google-chrome-google-entering-the-browser-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2008 02:36:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/09/02/google-chrome-google-entering-the-browser-market/</guid>
      <description>Yep, Google have entered the browser market with Google Chrome.
Although the press release was sent a little early, you can read an interesting comic book (PDF) here with some quite technical details on the ins and outs of Google&amp;rsquo;s newest plan for world domination philanthropic effort.
Webkit is the rendering engine, and the V8 team have created an entirely new JavaScript Virtual Machine to help make this browser super quick and stable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gmail hacking tool - do you access your email securely?</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/08/25/gmail-hacking-tool-do-you-access-your-email-securely/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2008 04:15:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/08/25/gmail-hacking-tool-do-you-access-your-email-securely/</guid>
      <description>Stumbled upon this article today detailing a Gmail hacking tool presented at the Defcon hackers&amp;rsquo; conference in Las Vegas which will be released in a week or so.
While news about the insecurity of accessing personal information without using encryption is really nothing new it serves as a timely reminder to secure ALL information you access online including email (not just your bank account!). So much detail of our personal and professional lives are held in our (primary) email account, so much so that if it was compromised the fallout could be quite devastating.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MySQL aliases (just like table names) are case sensitive on *nix</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/08/22/mysql-alias-just-like-table-names-are-case-sensitive-on-nix/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2008 03:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/08/22/mysql-alias-just-like-table-names-are-case-sensitive-on-nix/</guid>
      <description>As you might know when using MySQL on a case-sensitive OS (like Linux) you must reference your table names in a case sensitive manner. So if you have a table called products the following sample query will NOT work:
SELECT	productId FROM	Products  It won&amp;rsquo;t work because MySQL stores the table information in directories on the file system, therefore these directories are case sensitive. So your query must be as follows (note the lower case products):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2 cool things about Railo</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/08/16/2-cool-things-about-railo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2008 09:04:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/08/16/2-cool-things-about-railo/</guid>
      <description>Session management: If an application/session scope is defined with the tag or the application.cfc, in Railo it will not automatically exist. Only when the scope is used for the first time it will be created. If the scope is not used, it won&amp;rsquo;t be created either.
This is really good news. Many people have blogged in the past about issues with &amp;ldquo;bots&amp;rdquo; hitting ColdFusion sites and spawning a multitude of sessions which (depending on the application of course) can cause memory and/or performance problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FarCry 5 running on Railo 3 (Windows)</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/08/16/farcry-5-running-on-railo-3-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2008 08:15:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/08/16/farcry-5-running-on-railo-3-windows/</guid>
      <description>The CFML market is hotting up with Railo going open source (in version 3.1) and joining forces with JBoss for an end of 2008 release! With that in mind I figured it was time to check out Railo with the latest version of FarCry.
My environment:
 Windows XP Railo 3.0.0.003 FarCry 5.0.0 (although 5.0.2 is out, the latest distro from the site offers only 5.0.0) FarCry 5.0.2 MySQL 5  I&amp;rsquo;m using the &amp;ldquo;express&amp;rdquo; version of Railo which bundles with Jetty Application Server, so no need for any apache configurations as everything runs off port 8888.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>getmooh - automated callback service</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/08/13/getmooh-automated-callback-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2008 23:33:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/08/13/getmooh-automated-callback-service/</guid>
      <description>Looking to escape from a date or to get out of any sticky social situation?
Try this free online automated callback service called getmooh.

 It is designed to help you escape a variety of situations by calling you automatically on your phone at a pre-specified time and playing you a recording which will either instruct you on what to say to elude your tormentor(s), or which will simply give a convincing sense of you being on an important call.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding subscriptions to comments for your Wordpress theme</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/08/09/adding-subscriptions-to-comments-for-your-wordpress-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2008 03:13:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/08/09/adding-subscriptions-to-comments-for-your-wordpress-theme/</guid>
      <description>If you are using a Wordpress theme which doesn&amp;rsquo;t support users subscribing to comments (crazy I know) you can add the plugin Subscribe to comments which is currently at version 2.1
A summary of the features this plugin provides:
 Rudimentary security Recognition of subscription status Themeable subscription manager Ability to let users change notification e-mail address Easy integration into comments form Subscription without leaving a comment Customization Internationalization  Installation is as easy as you&amp;rsquo;d expect from a Wordpress plugin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Inkscape (0.46) to run on Mac Leopard</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/08/06/getting-inkscape-046-to-run-on-mac-leopard/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2008 01:09:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/08/06/getting-inkscape-046-to-run-on-mac-leopard/</guid>
      <description>Inscape is a fantastic open source vector graphics tool which can be a nice alternative to Adobe&amp;rsquo;s Illustrator.
Getting it to run on the Mac took a couple of extra steps though.
Firstly the download page advises that you upgrade X11.app to at least XQuartz v2.1.4. This is a large-ish download which forces you to quit all applications as it needs to restart your system after installing.
The next problem was that after a restart, Inkscape displays a message saying that the first time it runs it may take a while to load as it needs to caches fonts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Server Monitoring your ColdFusion sites using an alias</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/08/02/server-monitoring-your-coldfusion-sites-using-an-alias/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2008 03:19:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/08/02/server-monitoring-your-coldfusion-sites-using-an-alias/</guid>
      <description>I just read about a nice feature of the ColdFusion server monitor tool (available in ColdFusion 8) over on sandeepp&amp;rsquo;s blog.
Essentially within the server monitors settings screen you can setup an &amp;ldquo;alias&amp;rdquo; for any site which uses a front controller which a lot of sites do particularly if you are using any of the popular frameworks like FarCry, Mach-II, Fusebox and Model-Glue etc
This makes your projects much easier to trouble shoot and test.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Latest Firefox breaks FarCry 3 context menu</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/07/30/latest-firefox-breaks-farcry-3-context-menu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2008 04:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/07/30/latest-firefox-breaks-farcry-3-context-menu/</guid>
      <description>If the following describes your environment, this a reminder to upgrade and use the latest Farcry:
 Using Mac (OS X Leopard) Using FarCry v3 Using Firefox and have recently upgraded to version 3.0 or 3.0.1  The reason? Well the new upgrade of Firefox 3 has broken the webtop context menu. You can see the menu, but none of the options work.
Although you could use Camino which works well (and Safari isn&amp;rsquo;t fully suported on FarCry 3), you really should be upgrading to the brand spanking new FarCry 5 :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wordpress for mobile devices</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/07/25/wordpress-for-mobile-devices/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2008 00:55:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/07/25/wordpress-for-mobile-devices/</guid>
      <description>Wordpress is one of the most used blogging platforms around. One of the great things about it is the community support including the countless plugins you can use to enhance your blog/site.
Particularly with the iPhone and other smart devices, mobile web seems to be experiencing a surge in traffic and importance to businesses. Although a lot of these &amp;ldquo;smart&amp;rdquo; devices now have full-featured browsers which can certainly handle your site without resorting to an entirely different version for mobile, there are still millions of handsets which access the web without a sophisticated browser so you often need to have a separate version of your site or at least a different stylesheet to handle these devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do you lock your screen on a Mac?</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/07/22/how-do-you-lock-your-screen-on-a-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/07/22/how-do-you-lock-your-screen-on-a-mac/</guid>
      <description>Call me crazy, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem like you can &amp;ldquo;natively&amp;rdquo; lock your screen on a Mac like you can on Windows. Very odd and annoying as it&amp;rsquo;s something I do everytime I leave my workstation, I&amp;rsquo;ve even had to agree to a policy that I will never leave my workstation open as I have secure access to production servers (via ssh).
I found some craziness on google where users setup &amp;ldquo;hot corners&amp;rdquo; with mouse gestures with the idea that when you &amp;ldquo;drag your cursor&amp;rdquo; into that corner the screensaver will be activated requiring a password to get back to the desktop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>InetAddressLocator problems with FarCry 3</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/07/21/inetaddresslocator-problems-with-farcry-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2008 02:56:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/07/21/inetaddresslocator-problems-with-farcry-3/</guid>
      <description>Took me a little bit to find the solution for this across several different board posts so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d quickly write it up.
For those of us still using FarCry 3 (remember that FarCry 5 is out!) you may come across the following error:
&amp;ldquo;java init failed: net.sf.javainetloca­tor.InetAddressLocat­or&amp;rdquo;
The docs tell us:
 Geolocator is a plugin that determines the locale of an inbound request. Its an optional plugin that is turned off by default, and requires a class file InetAddressLocator to be placed in your class path.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another reminder of the importance of preventing SQL injection</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/07/19/another-reminder-of-the-importance-of-preventing-sql-injection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2008 01:59:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/07/19/another-reminder-of-the-importance-of-preventing-sql-injection/</guid>
      <description>Mark Kruger has another interesting and timely read about an ambitious SQL injection attack one of his clients recently experienced.
One things for sure, it&amp;rsquo;s certainly an interesting time to be a developer. Hackers and spammers make sure of that :(
SQL injection has been around for so long, it is truly a crime if developers (ColdFusion developers at least) aren&amp;rsquo;t using cfqueryparam for every WHERE clause in their queries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coding standards, do you use them?</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/07/17/coding-standards-do-you-use-them/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2008 22:52:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/07/17/coding-standards-do-you-use-them/</guid>
      <description>Reading a blog entry this morning got me thinking. Essentially the author had experienced problems (after installing the latest ColdFusion hotfix) with case sensitivity on a Linux server. Two of the issues where based around calling custom tags and createObject(), where the actual filename was in a different &amp;ldquo;case&amp;rdquo; to the code calling the tag or instansiating the object.
Why did this get me thinking? Coding standards.
What standards do you use when developing?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotatsu - a simple html table generator</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/07/08/kotatsu-a-simple-html-table-generator/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2008 09:53:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/07/08/kotatsu-a-simple-html-table-generator/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes you want to create an HTML table by hand and don&amp;rsquo;t have the luxury (if you consider it a luxury!) of having Dreamweaver around. Of course, creating HTML tables really isn&amp;rsquo;t all that difficult or time consuming, but considering we use snippets for just about everything else why not have a tool to generate these tables for us?
Kotatsu is an online tool to do just that, sure it is very simple (doesn&amp;rsquo;t support col/rowspans or accessibility attributes etc) but when you want to churn out a basic custom table it just might save you some time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t forget the ColdFusion site-wide error handler</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/07/08/dont-forget-the-coldfusion-site-wide-error-handler/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2008 02:55:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/07/08/dont-forget-the-coldfusion-site-wide-error-handler/</guid>
      <description>Most developers know and use exception handling techniques when building web apps. One of the important reasons to do this is so that the end user isn&amp;rsquo;t presented with an ugly server error message, but instead a nice &amp;ldquo;skinned&amp;rdquo; template advising them that something&amp;rsquo;s gone wrong and an administrator has been notified etc. (Of course another reason for this is not to give away sensitive server configuration information to prying eyes!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12 Breeds of Client and How to Work with Them</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/07/01/12-breeds-of-client-and-how-to-work-with-them/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 22:49:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/07/01/12-breeds-of-client-and-how-to-work-with-them/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve all experienced dealing with clients before, even if they are &amp;ldquo;internal&amp;rdquo; clients within our organisation. Today I saw this article on 12 Breeds of Client and How to Work with Them.
The article mentions 12 different types of client (like a low-tech or hands-on client), how to spot one, the highs and lows of dealing with them and how to work effectively together.
A good read :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pastebin - perfect for code collaboration</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/06/28/pastebin-perfect-for-code-collaboration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2008 02:43:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/06/28/pastebin-perfect-for-code-collaboration/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever pasted code you are working on to a colleague over IM or even email for some help or an opinion? Then you would benefit from using pastebin (free service) particularly if you experienced problems with code over IM in the past :(
&amp;ldquo;Pastebin is a tool for collaborative debugging or editing&amp;rdquo;
What that means is you can paste any code into a nice big textarea on the pastebin homepage, choose your syntax highlighting (ColdFusion is available!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New FarCry &#34;core&#34; site</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/06/23/new-farcry-core-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2008 23:56:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/06/23/new-farcry-core-site/</guid>
      <description>The guys at Daemon have been busy of late. With the conference just barely over I just noticed they&amp;rsquo;ve found the time to launch a new site at http://www.farcrycore.org/ for all your information needs on the FarCry framework.
Includes documentation, downloads (for the new version 5!) and more, go and take a look and try it out today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Careful when sharing code sent from an IM client</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/06/20/careful-when-copying-code-sent-from-an-im-client/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2008 07:28:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/06/20/careful-when-copying-code-sent-from-an-im-client/</guid>
      <description>Ok this is a warning to all those who get sent commands to use via IM.
Scenario:
I was helping someone setup their Apache config today, so I copied part of my VirtualHost block to them in an IM client. Then I went to their machine, grabbed the code and pasted it into their .conf file. Then Apache wouldn&amp;rsquo;t start/restart.
After spending 10 minutes scratching my head and comparing code and files etc&amp;hellip;I removed all carriage returns/whitespace from the code and woo hoo!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FarCry - Finding a page by &#39;typename&#39; somewhere above the current page</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/06/19/farcry-finding-a-page-by-typename-somewhere-above-the-current-page/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2008 00:47:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/06/19/farcry-finding-a-page-by-typename-somewhere-above-the-current-page/</guid>
      <description>Note: This is for FarCry v3 which is a bit old now but should work for v5 :)
Sometimes when using FarCry I have a need to find an occurance of a page &amp;ldquo;type&amp;rdquo; which sits somewhere above where I currently am in the the navigation hierachy.
Say I want to find the &amp;ldquo;VehicleType&amp;rdquo; page (which could be Car or Bike etc) above where I am in the navigation hierachy as listed below (when I&amp;rsquo;m on the &amp;ldquo;Models&amp;rdquo; page):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does your bank do online statements?</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/06/14/does-your-bank-do-online-statements/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2008 05:17:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/06/14/does-your-bank-do-online-statements/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a lucky member of the teachers credit union, lucky for many reasons but just one of them is that they offer online statements. Meaning you get no correspondence via traditional mail.
They are also donating $1 into the Teachers Environment Fund for each member who signs up for e-statements.
Ask yourself, do you really need all those paper statements every month? I know I don&amp;rsquo;t, which is why I&amp;rsquo;m lucky to have a bank which provides an alternative.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebDU over for another year :(</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/06/13/webdu-over-for-another-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2008 10:23:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/06/13/webdu-over-for-another-year/</guid>
      <description>Unfortunately WebDU has been and gone, all the good things go by so quickly :(
It was a fantastic event yet again and a HUGE thank you to Geoff, Julie, Vanessa and all the Daemonites for putting on a spectacular couple of days.
I don&amp;rsquo;t know what the highlight was, the great speakers/topics or the night of activities (bowling, pool, laser skirmish and drinking&amp;hellip;lots of drinking!).
One of the cool things about WebDU is the calibre of speakers it attracts from all over the globe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebDU starts tomorrow!!!</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/06/11/webdu-starts-tomorrow/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2008 12:57:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/06/11/webdu-starts-tomorrow/</guid>
      <description>Looking forward to another WebDU starting tomorrow in beautiful Sydney.
Geoff, Julie and the rest of the Daemon gang have brought us yet another stella cast of speakers. Judging from the agenda I&amp;rsquo;m going to have trouble knowing which session to attend, but that&amp;rsquo;s always a good thing.
Also can&amp;rsquo;t wait for the first evening party, something different this year to help everyone meet and greet.
I hope to see (and meet) some new faces and hopefully not be too worn out on Friday for day 2 :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PreserveSingleQuotes still breaks on array style parameters</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/06/11/preservesinglequotes-still-breaks-on-array-style-parameters/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2008 04:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/06/11/preservesinglequotes-still-breaks-on-array-style-parameters/</guid>
      <description>As far back as ColdFusion 6 PreserveSingleQuotes hasn&amp;rsquo;t worked with array style parameters.
#preserveSingleQuotes(aWhere[i])#  This was even submitted as ColdFusion Bug number 53977 on the CF6 docs, a few years later and we still have no joy for ColdFusion 8 :(
Structures will work but only when you access the value by dot notation, not using array style:
#preserveSingleQuotes(stWhere.i)#  This was annoying today when I wanted to loop over an array of &amp;ldquo;WHERE&amp;rdquo; clause arguments passed into a function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking for the source code of open source software? Use koders</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/06/09/looking-for-the-source-code-of-open-source-software-use-koders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2008 05:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/06/09/looking-for-the-source-code-of-open-source-software-use-koders/</guid>
      <description>I came across a cool search engine the other day called Koders which is &amp;ldquo;a free on-line search engine for open source software and other web-downloadable code.&amp;rdquo;
The cool thing about this is you can search for just about any and every language you can think of, and quickly browse the source code of open source projects. This can be a nice way to view the API docs or just to see if the project is what you&amp;rsquo;re looking for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Password strength checker</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/05/30/password-strength-checker/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2008 12:41:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/05/30/password-strength-checker/</guid>
      <description>We all know passwords are the bane of any internet users online experience. So many sites, each with their own authentication requirements.
I came across this handy site called passwordmeter to help test the strength of your passwords.
It&amp;rsquo;s cool because it gives you an instant visual response for your passwords based upon things like;
 Number of characters Upper and lower case Letters or numbers only etc  I typically use several passwords and found that I might need to strengthen them up, but I did have a couple which scored over 70% which is good :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up svn:externals with subclipse</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/05/22/setting-up-svnexternals-with-subclipse/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2008 07:30:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/05/22/setting-up-svnexternals-with-subclipse/</guid>
      <description>Setting up &amp;ldquo;externals&amp;rdquo; with subversion can assist you when you want to load external libraries into an existing project.
You may have a JavaScript validation framework which you re-use amongst many projects. Of course you don&amp;rsquo;t want to copy and paste the code into every project, what would happen then if you wanted to upgrade the codebase?
Using subclipse (in the Eclipse IDE) you can link a separate svn repository in the middle of your project by adding an svn:externals property.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>INSERT DELAYED with MySQL</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/05/22/insert-delayed-with-mysql/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/05/22/insert-delayed-with-mysql/</guid>
      <description>Yet another tip for MySQL users, INSERT DELAYED.
What does it do? Well when you execute your query MySQL will return an ok immediately to your application, and the request then gets queued to be INSERTED when the table in question is not being used by any other thread. This obviously means your application doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to sit around waiting for the INSERT to be completed which can have a positive impact on performance under load.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>INSERT or UPDATE in one statement with MySQL - performance test</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/04/24/insert-or-update-in-one-statement-with-mysql-performance-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2008 01:59:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/04/24/insert-or-update-in-one-statement-with-mysql-performance-test/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I posted on a handy MySQL feature where you can combine an INSERT and UPDATE on a record in the one statement.
Someone asked about the performance of this so I ran a little test to get some basic numbers.
One thing to note is that even when MySQL is actually UPDATING your record (ON DUPLICATE KEY UPDATE), the statement is being executed on the database as an INSERT and not an UPDATE statement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>INSERT or UPDATE in one statement with MySQL</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/04/23/insert-or-update-in-one-statement-with-mysql/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2008 02:09:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/04/23/insert-or-update-in-one-statement-with-mysql/</guid>
      <description>A little while ago I mentioned combining multiple INSERT statements with MySQL, here is another helpful approach to a common problem.
In many systems you will give the user a chance to ADD and EDIT a record, a News post for example. As usual there are many ways to handle writing any changes to the database, one common approach would be to have 2 methods in a News.cfc
E.g. create() and update()</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I hate spam: Spambot cracks Live Hotmail CAPTCHA</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/04/16/i-hate-spam-spambot-cracks-live-hotmail-captcha/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2008 23:04:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/04/16/i-hate-spam-spambot-cracks-live-hotmail-captcha/</guid>
      <description>Apparently the CAPTCHA for Windows Live Mail can be cracked in as little as 60 seconds and Gmail&amp;rsquo;s CAPTCHA has also been cracked.
Does this mean the beginning of the end for CAPTCHA?
There are some other interesting solutions to spambots out there, it&amp;rsquo;ll be interesting to see the future landscape of this infestation and the methods used to prevent it.
Read more here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workaround for cfscript bug in varscoper</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/04/08/workaround-for-cfscript-bug-in-varscoper/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2008 02:32:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/04/08/workaround-for-cfscript-bug-in-varscoper/</guid>
      <description>Those that use the sensational varscoper tool from Mike Schierberl know that cfscript is still a little experimental with the current release.
One of the things it can do is return variables that are actually &amp;ldquo;var&amp;rdquo; scoped as not var scoped when using cfscript. This seems to happen most often when you have a comment directly above the variable in question.
&amp;lt;cfscript&amp;gt; var column = 2;	//which column the pod is in var row = 3;	//which row the pod is on var newRow = 0; &amp;lt;/cfscript&amp;gt;  In the above example Varscoper tells me that &amp;ldquo;newRow&amp;rdquo; is not var scoped when clearly it is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flushing a cached web service</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/04/07/flushing-a-cached-web-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2008 06:07:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/04/07/flushing-a-cached-web-service/</guid>
      <description>When you use WebServices with ColdFusion, the WSDL &amp;lsquo;stub&amp;rsquo; is cached in CF Administrator (presumably for performance reasons).
This can be a pain when you need to change the WSDL and you don&amp;rsquo;t have access to CF Admin to flush the service which is the scenario I found myself in today.
Luckily for me I sit near some ColdFusion peeps who sorted me out with a little Java method (courtesy of the ServiceFactory) to flush a WSDL from a ColdFusion template.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Combining multiple INSERT statements with MySQL</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/04/03/combining-multiple-insert-statements-with-mysql/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2008 12:24:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/04/03/combining-multiple-insert-statements-with-mysql/</guid>
      <description>As all developers know, one of the most common bottlenecks in a web application is the database. Database optimisation is therefore a huge part of building a streamlined application capable of handling more concurrent users.
Often you might have the need to perform multiple INSERT&amp;rsquo;s against a database from a single user form submission.
Let&amp;rsquo;s say you had a form allowing a user to add their own web bookmarks (think a simple del.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating (ColdFusion) unscoped query variables</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/03/28/evaluating-coldfusion-unscoped-query-variables/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2008 01:29:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/03/28/evaluating-coldfusion-unscoped-query-variables/</guid>
      <description>Most developers know that if you reference a variable without a scope prefix (such as variables, form, URL etc) ColdFusion will check each of the available scopes until it finds a variable of the name you are looking for.
The order in which ColdFusion checks is:
 Function local (UDFs and CFCs only) Thread local (inside threads only) Arguments Variables (local scope) Thread CGI Cffile URL Form Cookie Client  *** Note:** Although the order above came from the Adobe docs I&amp;rsquo;m not sure about &amp;ldquo;cffile&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing PHP5 with MySQL extensions</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/03/24/installing-php5-with-mysql-extensions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2008 04:59:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/03/24/installing-php5-with-mysql-extensions/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m generally a ColdFusion programmer but occasionally I need to install PHP for one reason or another, the last couple of times has been to use Wordpress.
I remember the last time I did this (maybe 6 months ago) I had problems with connecting to MySQL because PHP 5 no longer bundles MySQL client libraries for the following reasons:
 Most systems these days already have the client library installed. Given the above, having multiple versions of the library can get messy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update for Java 6</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/03/22/update-for-java-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2008 04:20:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/03/22/update-for-java-6/</guid>
      <description>Sun have just released Java 6 update 5, looking at the release notes it doesn&amp;rsquo;t look as though the CFC issues for ColdFusion have been addressed yet, we can only hope though!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random database results with ColdFusion</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/03/21/random-database-results-with-coldfusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2008 03:58:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/03/21/random-database-results-with-coldfusion/</guid>
      <description>Today I was looking at returning random records purely from MySQL but was limited with large tables in getting all random results (not just a random starting seed).
I tried a ColdFusion solution instead.
First get all the primary keys from the table in question and create an array of the values (this works for numeric and non-numeric keys):
&amp;lt;cfquery name=&amp;quot;qGetPKs&amp;quot; datasource=&amp;quot;dsn&amp;quot;&amp;gt; SELECT Id FROM myTable &amp;lt;/cfquery&amp;gt; &amp;lt;cfset aIds = listToArray(valueList(qGetPKs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Returning random results with MySQL</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/03/21/returning-random-results-with-mysql/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2008 03:20:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/03/21/returning-random-results-with-mysql/</guid>
      <description>Selecting random query results is something we often need to do, whether it be a single row or a small record set. You may want to display a random list of &amp;ldquo;tips&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;facts&amp;rdquo;, a random &amp;ldquo;user&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;related product&amp;rdquo; etc.
The simplest and most common solution you find uses the MySQL rand() function (which can be used to create an integer from 0 to 1.0)
Solution 1 SELECT	[.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Options for accessing the ColdFusion 8 documentation</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/03/16/options-for-accessing-the-coldfusion-8-documentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2008 22:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/03/16/options-for-accessing-the-coldfusion-8-documentation/</guid>
      <description>ColdFusion developers have quite a few options when wanting to access full help documentation for ColdFusion 8 including:
 Livedocs CFQuickdocs ColdFusionDocs.com CFDocs on AIR CFML Reference Docs for the iPod ColdFusion 8 Help Files for Eclipse  The &amp;lsquo;source&amp;rsquo; of all these is the same (Livedocs) so which do you go with? Funnily enough the offical Adobe Livedocs is probably the last one I&amp;rsquo;d choose simply because it&amp;rsquo;s a little slow :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vince Bonfanti and the differences between BlueDragon versions?</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/03/16/vince-bonfanti-and-the-differences-between-bluedragon-versions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2008 04:47:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/03/16/vince-bonfanti-and-the-differences-between-bluedragon-versions/</guid>
      <description>More news on the differences between the commercial and open source offerings for Blue Dragon on Vince Bonfanti&amp;rsquo;s blog as well as the New Atlanta forums;
&amp;ldquo;The free open source edition of BlueDragon/J2EE will be fully featured, with only minor differences to remove dependencies on commercial libraries.&amp;rdquo;
Vince elaborated more on the NA Product forums:
 There will be three differences between the commericial and open source editions of BlueDragon/J2EE:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Passing extra parameters to Prototype observer handlers</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/03/11/passing-extra-parameters-to-prototype-observer-handlers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2008 02:26:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/03/11/passing-extra-parameters-to-prototype-observer-handlers/</guid>
      <description>Another tip from my Prototype travels&amp;hellip;
&amp;lsquo;Observers&amp;rsquo; let you create a listener for a user event, for example on a form submission you may want to run some client side validation before actually submitting the form.
Of course you can add &amp;lsquo;onsubmit()&amp;rsquo; in your  tag, but isn&amp;rsquo;t it much nicer to keep your markup clean of this type of thing?
In your dom:loaded observer you can &amp;lsquo;listen&amp;rsquo; for a form submission as follows:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Showing and hiding elements with CSS and JavaScript</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/03/10/showing-and-hiding-elements-with-css-and-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/03/10/showing-and-hiding-elements-with-css-and-javascript/</guid>
      <description>*** Note:** These examples reference the Prototype JavaScript framework.
Often I find that I want to load content onto a page but have its default view state as hidden until a user defined event makes it appear.
The problem is if I hide an element using a linked CSS file (with a class or Id style of {display:none;}) it seems I cannot show that element using either of the following JavaScript options:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Better YouTube Firefox Extension</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/03/06/better-youtube-firefox-extension/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2008 03:21:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/03/06/better-youtube-firefox-extension/</guid>
      <description>This is cool, a little Firefox addon from the guys at lifehacker to make your youtube experience a little richer :)
It basically combines several Greasemonkey scripts together into a single package.
Features include:
 smartly enlarges videos for better viewing hides user comments declutters the page disables autoplay  Download and install the addon, restart Firefox and you&amp;rsquo;re set to go. To edit the preferences you need to go to:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Always add the &lt;cfimport&gt; tag when using cfimport style syntax</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/03/03/always-add-the-cfimport-tag-when-using-cfimport-style-syntax/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2008 00:32:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/03/03/always-add-the-cfimport-tag-when-using-cfimport-style-syntax/</guid>
      <description>Using cfimport is a great way to add custom tag functionality to your applications.
One thing you need to do of course is add a  tag to every template where you want to use the cfimport syntax. However, a couple of times when I&amp;rsquo;ve been creating new templates I&amp;rsquo;ve forgotten this rule and not added  and subsequently gotten confused when my results aren&amp;rsquo;t as expected.
I think the annoying thing is that ColdFusion does not throw an error in these situations, it just does nothing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Converting boolean values to numeric equivalents</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/03/02/converting-boolean-values-to-numeric-equivalents/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2008 23:32:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/03/02/converting-boolean-values-to-numeric-equivalents/</guid>
      <description>Today I had a situation where I wanted to convert a boolean value (true or false) to a numeric equivalent (1 or 0) for insertion into a database table field which had a &amp;ldquo;tinyint&amp;rdquo; data type.
The value was coming from a form checkbox, so the actual element may or may not exist in the form struct depending on whether the user &amp;ldquo;checked&amp;rdquo; the box or not.
I found a few ways to do this, some &amp;ldquo;better&amp;rdquo; than others but all using structKeyExists() to look for the form element.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can&#39;t access shared music with Rhythmbox (Ubuntu)?</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/02/28/cant-access-shared-music-with-rhythmbox-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2008 06:21:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/02/28/cant-access-shared-music-with-rhythmbox-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>Probably quite old news for those in the know, but if you&amp;rsquo;re using Rhythmbox to play music on Ubuntu and want to listen to shared music over a network where people are using iTunes version 7+&amp;hellip;.it ain&amp;rsquo;t going to work :(
You can view who is sharing music, but their actual libraries won&amp;rsquo;t load into Rhythmbox. In this case it&amp;rsquo;s not a compatibility between OS&amp;rsquo;s etc, it&amp;rsquo;s purely proprietary :(</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing the cfeclipse &#39;tag insight&#39; delay time</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/02/28/changing-the-cfeclipse-tag-insight-delay-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2008 00:56:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/02/28/changing-the-cfeclipse-tag-insight-delay-time/</guid>
      <description>Having &amp;lsquo;tag insight&amp;rsquo; is a great part of any IDE, one which almost every developer takes advantage of irrespective of which editor they use. Tag insight of course being when your IDE provides information (attribute or return information etc) about the tag or function you are currently typing.
Normally when writing a function or tag like , when you hit the space bar and wait a second a little popup appears detailing exactly what you can do with this tag.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Tip: How to structure your queryparams</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/02/26/code-tip-how-to-structure-your-queryparams/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2008 04:16:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/02/26/code-tip-how-to-structure-your-queryparams/</guid>
      <description>If I were a betting man I&amp;rsquo;d bet a LOT of money (and perhaps even the house!) that you&amp;rsquo;ve done this before.
Try to spot the error in the query below:
&amp;lt;cfquery name=&amp;quot;qCreate&amp;quot; datasource=&amp;quot;#getDSN()#&amp;quot;&amp;gt; INSERT INTO	myTable ( ObjectId, Country, DateOfBirth, Email, FirstName, Gender, LastName, MainSchoolId, PhoneHome, PhoneMobile, PostCode, State, Street, StudentId, StudentPassword, StudentPodId, Suburb ) VALUES ( &amp;lt;cfqueryparam cfsqltype=&amp;quot;cf_sql_varchar&amp;quot; value=&amp;quot;#createUUID()#&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;cfqueryparam cfsqltype=&amp;quot;cf_sql_varchar&amp;quot; value=&amp;quot;#arguments.oUser.get(&#39;country&#39;)#&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;cfqueryparam cfsqltype=&amp;quot;cf_sql_date&amp;quot; value=&amp;quot;#createODBCDate(arguments.oUser.get(&#39;dateOfBirth&#39;))#&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;cfqueryparam cfsqltype=&amp;quot;cf_sql_varchar&amp;quot; value=&amp;quot;#arguments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cfdocs on air (livedocs for CF8)</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/02/21/cfdocs-on-air-livedocs-for-cf8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2008 22:33:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/02/21/cfdocs-on-air-livedocs-for-cf8/</guid>
      <description>Brian Love recently released an AIR application he wrote which wraps up the ColdFusion 8 &amp;lsquo;livedocs&amp;rsquo;.
This is a great idea and a fantastic tool to add to your list. I&amp;rsquo;m sure most developers use livedocs as a reference (I do all the time) but historically the are SO slow (not to mention that I think Adobe needs to invest in a little SEO as I often get CF6 livedocs at the top of Google results!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using MySQL Administrator to view real time stats</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/02/21/using-mysql-administrator-to-view-real-time-stats/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2008 06:49:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/02/21/using-mysql-administrator-to-view-real-time-stats/</guid>
      <description>I was working on piece of code today which was sending an Ajax request to the server. The result of this request could have been 0 - 5 database UPDATE statements.
What I needed was a way to test my code to make sure the correct number of database statements were being executed based on the user event which fired the request.
There are of course a number of ways I could have done this including:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A couple more cool Firefox tips</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/02/18/a-couple-more-cool-firefox-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2008 20:50:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/02/18/a-couple-more-cool-firefox-tips/</guid>
      <description>Another couple of cool Firefox features which most people probably already know about.
How many times have you closed a tab only to realise &amp;ldquo;Damn&amp;hellip;I still wanted that open!&amp;rdquo;? Well I do that about everyday and although you have the general history manager&amp;hellip;if you&amp;rsquo;ve visited 100 sites that day it&amp;rsquo;s a pain to wade through to find the tab you just closed.
Instead you can visit the History menu and see the item &amp;ldquo;Recently Closed Tabs&amp;rdquo; for a list of the last 10 viewed tabs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The only valid measurement of code quality</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/02/07/the-only-valid-measurement-of-code-quality/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2008 00:05:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/02/07/the-only-valid-measurement-of-code-quality/</guid>
      <description>A friend of mine Don sent me this yesterday:
 Gold!  :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t ever user www.templatesbrowser.com for wordpress themes</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/01/24/dont-ever-user-wwwtemplatesbrowsercom-for-wordpress-themes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2008 04:43:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/01/24/dont-ever-user-wwwtemplatesbrowsercom-for-wordpress-themes/</guid>
      <description>Today I noticed a JavaScript error on my site, on investigation I saw the following JavaScript code in the page source:
var CCounter=2151068; var CCsite=www.chapter31.com; CCinvisible=0; &amp;lt;nosc/ript&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a hreflang=&amp;quot;de&amp;quot; lang=&amp;quot;de&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;http://www.portalux.com/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;online casino&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/nosc/ript&amp;gt; var CCounter=2151068; var CCsite=www.chapter31.com; CCinvisible=0;  My investigations found that where I downloaded the template from was a nice (NOT) little site called http://www.templatesbrowser.com/. Now what they do is add a &amp;ldquo;functions.php&amp;rdquo; file in the original code base, then call a method from the footer &amp;ldquo;credits();&amp;rdquo; which is in the functions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When to use form POST vs GET?</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/01/24/when-to-use-form-post-vs-get/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2008 03:01:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/01/24/when-to-use-form-post-vs-get/</guid>
      <description>I read a post today from Mark Kruger where he was warning against the possible side effects when using GET as a form submit method.
I think I (unintentionally) offended Mark with my comment where I asked why would anyone EVER use GET? because I pretty much always use POST so was wondering why you would use GET.
In my search for answers I asked Mark Lynch who seems to always have the answer to my questions :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking advantage of DOM on ready and Event observers using Prototype.js</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2008/01/23/taking-advantage-of-dom-on-ready-and-event-observers-using-prototypejs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2008 10:44:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2008/01/23/taking-advantage-of-dom-on-ready-and-event-observers-using-prototypejs/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing some JavaScript development with Prototype over the last few days and it&amp;rsquo;s been interesting trying to do things that I know how to do in jQuery, but in Prototype.
One of the cool things I like with all these JavaScript frameworks is the easy way they allow you to execute code on &amp;lsquo;DOM Ready&amp;rsquo; (once the page markup has completed but before all the images etc have loaded).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mylyn plugin for Aptana</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2007/12/18/mylyn-plugin-for-aptana/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2007 04:27:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2007/12/18/mylyn-plugin-for-aptana/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading about Mylyn for a little while now but haven&amp;rsquo;t had the opportunity to install it. After reading this post today from Adam Flater I thought it was about time I gave it a go.
For those that don&amp;rsquo;t know Mylyn:
 Mylyn is the Task-Focused UI for Eclipse that reduces information overload and makes multi-tasking easy. It does this by making tasks a first class part of Eclipse, and integrating rich and offline editing for repositories such as Bugzilla, Trac, and JIRA</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enforcing your Service as an API</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2007/12/08/enforcing-your-service-as-an-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2007 06:36:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2007/12/08/enforcing-your-service-as-an-api/</guid>
      <description>A lot ColdFusion developers are moving (or already there) towards a more OOP style of development. They have an understanding of and use several techniques and design patterns when building applications, particularly when it relates to things such as MVC and n-tiered development.
A small part of this is grouping related files withing separate directories in you application. Take &amp;lsquo;User&amp;rsquo; related files as an example where you&amp;rsquo;ll probably need some kind of a business object (User.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search and replace using reg exp</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2007/12/08/search-and-replace-using-reg-exp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2007 05:26:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2007/12/08/search-and-replace-using-reg-exp/</guid>
      <description>The other day Nathan Strutz wrote a great post on finding and replacing text in your IDE (in my case I&amp;rsquo;m using Aptana/cfeclipse) using regular expressions.
This is more a reminder to me so that I try to use it (with the idea that it&amp;rsquo;ll become 2nd nature!), but I also had a play to see how I could use it in day to day coding. I&amp;rsquo;m sure others have more interesting uses, but here is where I can use it immediately:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flex not working on Ubuntu using the Gnash player</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2007/11/14/flex-not-working-on-ubuntu-using-the-gnash-player/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2007 00:38:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2007/11/14/flex-not-working-on-ubuntu-using-the-gnash-player/</guid>
      <description>Gnash is a free Flash movie player for Ubuntu which works as a standalone player or as a plugin for Firefox and Konqueror.
This is the default (I believe) player installed on Ubuntu 7.10 (the Adobe player isn&amp;rsquo;t there by default).
I recently tried to load a Flex app in this player and failed, the reason is that Gnash is in alpha state and supports Flash version 7 (and some AS classes for 8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Google Mail as your local SMTP server</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2007/11/13/using-google-mail-as-your-local-smtp-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2007 04:27:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2007/11/13/using-google-mail-as-your-local-smtp-server/</guid>
      <description>As a server-side developer you are often sending emails from your web application, whether those emails be for debugging/exception handling or actual application functionality (such as a contact form etc).
Although some developers decide to turn off mail debugging locally (and instead view the errors inline), you pretty much always have the need to send emails from your development environment.
In the past I have either connected to a staging mail server or used a free SMTP server (installed locally on my workstation) like MailEnable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making your web applications platform independant</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2007/11/02/making-your-web-applications-platform-independant/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2007 05:27:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2007/11/02/making-your-web-applications-platform-independant/</guid>
      <description>I was looking for some information the other day about line separators across Windows/MAC/Linux etc when I stumbled upon 3 great articles from Christian Cantrell.
Although the articles are quite old they were very informative for me so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d share them in case others didn&amp;rsquo;t know this already.
Making Your ColdFusion Applications More Platform Independent (Part I) Basically about case sensitive filenames which is very important on *nix, but also included the following which I&amp;rsquo;ve never heard and to be honest would like to test:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CFML reference docs for the iPod</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2007/11/01/cfml-reference-docs-for-the-ipod/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2007 02:30:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2007/11/01/cfml-reference-docs-for-the-ipod/</guid>
      <description>That&amp;rsquo;s right, the ColdFusion 8 quick docs for Apple&amp;rsquo;s iPod!
I found this one a while ago and quickly tried it out and it&amp;rsquo;s really cool :)
I get public transport to and from work everyday so I find it easy and convenient to read up on the new functions and tags for CF8. Beats just standing there right?
Read more and give it a try here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ColdFusion 8 can now use cacheAfter/cacheWithin when using cfqueryparam&#39;s</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2007/10/31/coldfusion-8-can-now-use-cacheaftercachewithin-when-using-cfqueryparams/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2007 22:19:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2007/10/31/coldfusion-8-can-now-use-cacheaftercachewithin-when-using-cfqueryparams/</guid>
      <description>I just noticed this in the Adobe docs for cfqueryparam in ColdFusion 8:
 Revised 8/21/2007: Removed limitation on using the cfquery cachedAfter or cachedWithin attributes with cfqueryparam.This limit no longer applies.
 This is great news because before (MX7 and below):
 You cannot use the cfquery cachedAfter or cachedWithin attributes with cfqueryparam.
 I know many people didn&amp;rsquo;t like this limitation as it meant you needed to go to extra lengths to perform query caching (such as Application scope etc).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Styling issues when generating an xls from HTML</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2007/10/18/styling-issues-when-generating-an-xls-from-html/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2007 01:31:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2007/10/18/styling-issues-when-generating-an-xls-from-html/</guid>
      <description>A few notes to self on generating .xls files from HTML tables, particularly with CSS.
It appears that excel only has a particular &amp;lsquo;range&amp;rsquo; of hex numbers you can use (at least for background colours). I was trying to use #eeeeee; for a while (which is obviously fine for HTML and for creating a PDF), but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t use that as a value in excel as the colours just weren&amp;rsquo;t displaying.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ColdFusion &#39;Round()&#39; docs inaccurate?</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2007/10/12/coldfusion-round-docs-inaccurate/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2007 05:26:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2007/10/12/coldfusion-round-docs-inaccurate/</guid>
      <description>Today I needed a function which would return me a whole number, rounding either up or down depending on whether the value passed to the function was less than or greater than .5
Looking at round() ColdFusion 8 docs they say:
 Rounds a number to the closest integer that is larger than the input parameter.
 Hmm, that doesn&amp;rsquo;t sound right.
In actual fact the round() function does exactly what it should, rounds numbers down OR up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can&#39;t set a scheduled task &#39;End Date&#39; </title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2007/10/08/cant-set-a-scheduled-task-end-date/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2007 05:06:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2007/10/08/cant-set-a-scheduled-task-end-date/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve just created some functionality which will be executed by a ColdFusion (8 standard on Win 2003) scheduled task daily, but only for 1 month.
When I add my new task in ColdFusion administrator I can set the &amp;lsquo;Start Date&amp;rsquo; ok, but not the &amp;lsquo;End Date&amp;rsquo;. The reason? Well I&amp;rsquo;m not sure, but it looks like a conflict in US/European date formats (I&amp;rsquo;m located in Australia and the server region settings are English/Australia).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>createODBCDate() returns &#39;time&#39; as well?</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2007/10/05/createodbcdate-returns-time-as-well/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2007 05:30:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2007/10/05/createodbcdate-returns-time-as-well/</guid>
      <description>Recently I was just comparing 2 dates (one from a query and the other was now()) using the createODBCDate() and dateCompare() functions.
I was using the createODBCDate() function because I only wanted the &amp;lsquo;date&amp;rsquo; part of a date object, not the &amp;lsquo;time&amp;rsquo;. More than likely I should have been using dateFormat(), but that&amp;rsquo;s another story :)
I had the following:
&amp;lt;cfif dateCompare(createODBCDate(q.DateTimeCreated), createODBCDate(now())) EQ 0&amp;gt;  The problem was I kept getting -1 returned, meaning that &amp;lsquo;q.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Caveat when calling components from onSessionEnd()</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2007/09/28/caveat-when-calling-components-from-onsessionend/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2007 03:19:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2007/09/28/caveat-when-calling-components-from-onsessionend/</guid>
      <description>As most ColdFusion developers know, you cannot reference &amp;lsquo;application&amp;rsquo; scoped variables directly in Application.cfc&amp;rsquo;s onSessionEnd() method. Instead you need to use the ApplicationScope parameter. Notes from the docs:
 You must use the ApplicationScope parameter to access the Application scope. You cannot reference the Application scope directly; for example, use Arguments.ApplicationScope.myVariable, not Application.myVariable. Use a named lock when you reference variables in the Application scope, as shown in the example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jQuery and SWFObject conflict</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2007/09/28/jquery-and-swfobject-conflict/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2007 01:27:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2007/09/28/jquery-and-swfobject-conflict/</guid>
      <description>I experienced some strange behaviour today when building a site which was using jQuery and SWFObject. Our Flash files were loading ok and 99% of the javascript (using jQuery) was working fine.
The problem was found only in IE (sound familiar?) with the following code:
$(document).ready(function(){ $(&#39;#submitButton&#39;).click(function(){  When the &amp;lsquo;submitButton&amp;rsquo; was clicked, this function was not firing in IE. After some googling I found that there is a slight conflict with jQuery and SWFObject.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a custom FarCry login page</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2007/09/27/creating-a-custom-farcry-login-page/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2007 01:08:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2007/09/27/creating-a-custom-farcry-login-page/</guid>
      <description>The FarCry security model is really very cool. You can of course setup users within the &amp;lsquo;admin&amp;rsquo; area and assign those users to groups (and those groups can have different permissions), but you can also authenticate via Active Directory or LDAP etc.
One thing you can also do with ease is secure particular navigation &amp;lsquo;nodes&amp;rsquo; of the website, thus quickly and easily creating password protected &amp;lsquo;member&amp;rsquo; areas.
Whenever you secure a navigation branch the user is presented with the default FarCry login screen as seen below:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ColdFire 1.0 released</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2007/09/27/coldfire-10-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2007 00:13:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2007/09/27/coldfire-10-released/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday there was some news from Ray and Nathan Mische regarding the 1.0 release of ColdFire, Nathan has a great write up here.
From RIAForge:
 ColdFire is an extension to FireBug. It provides debug information in a FireBug tab as opposed to the bottom of the page. This lets you debug and keep your site layout intact, since ColdFusion&amp;rsquo;s built-in debug information can sometimes mess with your site layout.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google analytics AIR app</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2007/09/25/google-analytics-air-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2007 02:26:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2007/09/25/google-analytics-air-app/</guid>
      <description>An interesting AIR app has been released in Beta for Google analytics.
From the author:
 The Google Analytics Reporting suite is an Adobe AIR application that brings Google Analytics to the desktop. It uses itâ€™s own custom API to interact with Google and nearly implements all features of Analytics.
 You can even export the data to PDF, XLS (Excel) and XML.
Nice :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hostmysite not quite as stable as I&#39;d like</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2007/08/22/hostmysite-not-quite-as-stable-as-id-like/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2007 00:45:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2007/08/22/hostmysite-not-quite-as-stable-as-id-like/</guid>
      <description>I know most rave about how good hostmysite are. They do have great support and competitive plans, but even for a shared plan (CF+) I have had the same issues for a few months now.
My issue is simple, they seem to restart JRun on average 5-6 times per day. PER DAY!
Hmm, is this not a little too frequent? I have a couple of sites on there and it seems everytime I visit the site (5-6 times a day) the application restarts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;localURL&#34; attribute added to cfdocument in ColdFusion 8</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2007/08/16/localurl-attribute-added-to-cfdocument-in-coldfusion-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2007 09:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2007/08/16/localurl-attribute-added-to-cfdocument-in-coldfusion-8/</guid>
      <description>I was debugging a legacy app today which I&amp;rsquo;d just migrated to a new server running ColdFusion 8. A part of this application generates a PDF using . As usual it was working fine on my development and staging environments&amp;hellip;but not on production! Damn.
After a bit of fiddling I found a related post by Rupesh Kumar where he mentions that you may have problems if ColdFusion is behind a firewall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Aptana IDE is busted</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2007/08/14/my-aptana-ide-is-busted/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2007 05:45:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2007/08/14/my-aptana-ide-is-busted/</guid>
      <description>Hmm, running with my past history of having that &amp;lsquo;special&amp;rsquo; touch with computers&amp;hellip;my version of Aptana (Aptana IDE (build 0.2.8.15637)) has busted.
Kaput.
Not happy Jan.
I was running an Aptana update yesterday when the network went down. Everything seemed fine until I went to restart Apatana and got the following:
Damn
Damn
Damn
No fix as yet and roughly 500 lines in the .log file everytime I try to start up telling me I have a hell of a lot of missing bundles :(</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Storing Flash, ColdFusion and SQL in subversion</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2007/08/13/storing-flash-coldfusion-and-sql-in-subversion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2007 23:28:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2007/08/13/storing-flash-coldfusion-and-sql-in-subversion/</guid>
      <description>Most developers who use Source Code Management are familiar with the fact that while you can have any directory you want in your &amp;lsquo;repositories&amp;rsquo;, it is recommended that you use the following directories as a base layout:
 branches
 tags
 trunk
  The trunk directory will hold the &amp;ldquo;main line&amp;rdquo; of development, a branches directory will have &amp;ldquo;branch-ing&amp;rdquo; development (perhaps a maintenance release?), and a tags directory holds a &amp;ldquo;snapshot&amp;rdquo; in time (essentially a read-only area) often used when deploying to a production server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facebook homepage source code found!</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2007/08/12/facebook-homepage-source-code-found/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2007/08/12/facebook-homepage-source-code-found/</guid>
      <description>Hmm, seems a problem with the .htaccess file made the source for Facebooks homepage available.
Nik Cubrilovic offers an explanation from a technical standpoint:
 PHP has always been notorious for sometimes not processing requests poorly and sending back the source code for pages to the client. Because of the way mod_php works with apache, if mod_php fails in intercepting and processing the request, then apache will just serve it back to the client as an ordinary text file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&lt;cfmail&gt; failto only accepts a single address?</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2007/08/03/cfmail-failto-only-accepts-a-single-address/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2007 01:50:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2007/08/03/cfmail-failto-only-accepts-a-single-address/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m getting some new production servers setup at the moment and I have a single ColdFusion application ready to go on one of them.
Part of the setup was of course getting an SMTP server going, to test this I used a simple ColdFusion script with a cfmail tag. I was receiving the email successfully so all was good&amp;hellip;until I tested sending emails as part of my application flow, no email :(</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detecting and redirecting http to https</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2007/07/21/detecting-and-redirecting-http-to-https/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2007 05:43:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2007/07/21/detecting-and-redirecting-http-to-https/</guid>
      <description>There was a recent thread on the mach-ii mailing list where a user wanted to detect whether a request was being made via http or https.
This is quite a common step developers take when working on a site with secure (SSL) and non-secure areas. As the list is mach-ii there are a couple of obvious framework specific options to take, those being Filters and Plugins. Although Peter Farrel does have an sslPlugin available, I liked the approach put forward by Matt Osbun:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OT: I HATE ads on CFDJ</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2007/06/22/ot-i-hate-ads-on-cfdj/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2007 01:20:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2007/06/22/ot-i-hate-ads-on-cfdj/</guid>
      <description>Ok&amp;hellip;
I understand (though I&amp;rsquo;m not happy) that advertising is a part of our everyday lives and &amp;lsquo;online&amp;rsquo; is no exception.
I understand that to subsidise costs, many sites have to display advertising to bring us (the audience) great content. These ads are usually in the form of banners or inline (adsense) textual ads etc.
I understand all of this but what I HATE is video based advertising.
I&amp;rsquo;m really not trying to pick on these guys, but the ColdFusion Developers Journal currently has video ads on most (all?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inspirational posts from the community</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2007/06/17/inspirational-posts-from-the-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2007 23:50:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2007/06/17/inspirational-posts-from-the-community/</guid>
      <description>Like a lot of people I spend quite a bit of time reading the technical blogs as a constant source of knowledge and advancement.
A couple of posts both inspired and got me thinking over the weekend so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d quickly mention both in case anybody missed them, they&amp;rsquo;re a great read.
The first was by Ben Nadel on a book called The Dip which is subtitled &amp;ldquo;A Little Book That Teaches You When To Quit (And When To Stick)&amp;rdquo; and delivers a huge message:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using variables.instance inside your components</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2007/06/14/using-variablesinstance-inside-your-components/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2007 08:36:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2007/06/14/using-variablesinstance-inside-your-components/</guid>
      <description>Often when creating ColdFusion components developers will create a structure to hold component instance data. This data is stored in the components &amp;lsquo;variables&amp;rsquo; scope and is therefore available to all methods.
Here is an example from the rooibos component generator:
&amp;lt;cfcomponent displayname=&amp;quot;sample&amp;quot; output=&amp;quot;false&amp;quot; hint=&amp;quot;A bean which models the form.&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;!--- PROPERTIES ---&amp;gt; &amp;lt;cfset variables.instance = StructNew() /&amp;gt;  Now some of you may be wondering why you would use the extra struct level of &amp;lsquo;instance&amp;rsquo; when we already know everything in that struct is in the components instance (variables) scope.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading blogs on a mac using Firefox</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2007/06/13/reading-blogs-on-a-mac-using-firefox/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2007 23:54:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2007/06/13/reading-blogs-on-a-mac-using-firefox/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been on a Mac (OSX) for a little while now and generally I&amp;rsquo;m having a nice time, except when it comes to reading some (but only some) blogs!
We all know that font sizes are different across browser and platform, but Firefox on a mac occasionally makes life a little difficult particularly when it comes to reading comments and code snippets.
Here is a screen grab of an example, certainly not to pick on this particular blog but just one of the few examples I come across on my daily travels thru fullasagoog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Image manipulation with imageCFC v2.14</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2007/04/25/image-manipulation-with-imagecfc-v214/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2007 23:20:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2007/04/25/image-manipulation-with-imagecfc-v214/</guid>
      <description>Update: as of May 30th 2007 version 2.17 has been released! See the site for more information
Ok so I&amp;rsquo;m a little late on this one, but the new version of imageCFC (v2.14) was released on March 7th 2007. The big feature add is exact size thumbnails using the &amp;ldquo;cropToExact&amp;rdquo; argument of the &amp;ldquo;resize()&amp;rdquo; method:
 This argument, when combined with a specified width, specified height, and the preserveAspect argument being set to true will cause a image to be resized then cropped to fit exactly within the specified dimensions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unwanted ColdFusion form validation</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2007/04/24/unwanted-coldfusion-form-validation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2007 08:06:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2007/04/24/unwanted-coldfusion-form-validation/</guid>
      <description>I came across something strange today when developing a web form.
Basically I had a form field with a name/id of &amp;ldquo;restoration_required&amp;rdquo; but when I submitted the form I got the following error:
Now Geoff Bowers happened to be standing nearby and was kind enough to point out that this looked like a  validation error, only I wasn&amp;rsquo;t using cfform!
A quick test (on WinXP, CFMX 7.0.2) showed everything working as expected when I renamed the field as &amp;ldquo;restoration_isRequired&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Farcry 4.0 filename standards</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2007/04/23/farcry-40-filename-standards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2007 13:21:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2007/04/23/farcry-40-filename-standards/</guid>
      <description>Here at Daemon we are looking at standardising the FarCry core codebase in an effort to reduce any case-sensitivity issues that may be found when running FarCry on different platforms.
These problems usually arise when dealing with filenames of any type (.cfc, .cfm etc), indeed I ran into an issue today with an external developer who had created their own templates which weren&amp;rsquo;t showing up in the FarCry webtop. Filename case-sensitivity was the culprit :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Combining insert and update SQL logic</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2007/04/11/combining-update-and-insert-sql-logic/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2007 06:40:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2007/04/11/combining-update-and-insert-sql-logic/</guid>
      <description>*Note that this example is using MSSQL with an Identity set to generate the primary key automatically.
An all too common process developers go through when building database driven web applications is creating logic to INSERT a record when one doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist, and UPDATE a record when one does exist.
This often leads to conditional logic within your application (inside a Service layer perhaps) and then running one of 2 SQL statements depending on the existance of a primary key value which may be coming from a form or URL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cfquery &#39;result&#39; attribute caveat</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2007/04/10/cfquery-result-attribute-caveat/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2007 03:40:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2007/04/10/cfquery-result-attribute-caveat/</guid>
      <description>A great feature of  which was introduced in CFMX7 is the addition of the &amp;lsquo;result&amp;rsquo; attribute. When used, a developer can access a Structure of query result variables including the following keys:
 Cache ColumnList ExecutionTime RecordCount SQL SQLParameters  You can read more about the &amp;lsquo;result&amp;rsquo; attribute in a previous post or at Live docs.
One thing I&amp;rsquo;ve come across is that the structure returned (by using the result attribute) is created where the query is executed and the value of &amp;lsquo;result&amp;rsquo; references this struct in the local variable scope.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The &#39;coolest&#39; DHTML calendar</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2007/03/25/the-coolest-dhtml-calendar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2007 07:25:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2007/03/25/the-coolest-dhtml-calendar/</guid>
      <description>As web developers we are often some of the first people to see the newer techniques and tools available for use in web applications. This can be great as we can then hurry off and implement these things into our new projects.
But of course there are still millions of older sites (which will no doubt still be around for years to come!) using old techniques and tools. Ugh!
One of the more common things you find is the age old popup calendar window which is SLOW and could be blocked by the numerous popup blockers out there today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adobe Feature Request/Bug Report Form</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2007/02/04/adobe-feature-requestbug-report-form/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2007 07:50:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2007/02/04/adobe-feature-requestbug-report-form/</guid>
      <description>There was a lot of talk flying around the blogosphere over the last few months regarding the much anticipated ColdFusion 8 with a lot of people blogging their &amp;lsquo;wishlist&amp;rsquo; for the new version (codenamed Scorpio).
But one thing you might not have known (I certainly didn&amp;rsquo;t) is that there is an official form on the Adobe site where you can post a &amp;lsquo;bug&amp;rsquo; or request a new &amp;lsquo;feature&amp;rsquo;. Another &amp;ldquo;can&amp;rsquo;t believe I didn&amp;rsquo;t know that&amp;rdquo; :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cfqueryparam and conditional handling of NULL&#39;s</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2007/02/04/cfqueryparam-and-conditional-handling-of-nulls/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2007 06:45:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2007/02/04/cfqueryparam-and-conditional-handling-of-nulls/</guid>
      <description>Most people know that you should always use cfqueryparam on your query parameters when querying a database to (among other things):
 secure your database from unauthorised/malicious users perform data validation take advantage of SQL bind parameters  The cfqueryparam tag can and should be used whether the query be a SELECT, UPDATE, DELETE or INSERT.
One of the problems I&amp;rsquo;ve had in the past is when I want to either INSERT or UPDATE a column which has an INT datatype (MSSQL), but that column is not mandatory and therefore allows NULL values.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ColdFusion UUID and MSSQL newID()</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2007/01/30/coldfusion-uuids-and-mssql-newid/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2007 00:25:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2007/01/30/coldfusion-uuids-and-mssql-newid/</guid>
      <description>A lot of web applications these days use a UUID as the primary key instead of the int/identity combination (speaking for MSSQL that is).
Now there is a (valid) argument that UUID&amp;rsquo;s aren&amp;rsquo;t great for primary keys due to the fact that primary keys are clustered, meaning that integers would work much better if the table had a large amount of data. This may not effect you dramatically as you&amp;rsquo;d would most likely only see performance degradation once the database had a substantial amount of data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To delete or not to delete</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2007/01/11/to-delete-or-not-to-delete/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2007 12:19:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2007/01/11/to-delete-or-not-to-delete/</guid>
      <description>As a web developer you are constantly faced with building functionality to remove an object from an application. The object could be anything from a web page in a CMS to a user in a CRM, but generally involves a record(s) stored in a database.
For a user &amp;lsquo;using&amp;rsquo; the application whenever they access the functionality to remove the object it disappears from view&amp;hellip;but what happens behind the scenes?
There are a couple of standard options available to developers:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scriptprotect in CFMX7</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/12/21/scriptprotect-in-cfmx7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2006 04:43:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/12/21/scriptprotect-in-cfmx7/</guid>
      <description>I only recently found out about scriptprotect which is a cool new feature of ColdFusion MX7. Scriptprotect basically specifies whether to protect variables from cross-site scripting attacks, and can be enabled 2 ways.
The first is a server setting in ColdFusion Administrator. Go to &amp;lsquo;Settings&amp;rsquo; and check the &amp;ldquo;Enable global script protection&amp;rdquo; checkbox. This will obviously effect all sites running on that ColdFusion instance but can be overridden in each sites Application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>eclipse/cfeclipse gives me a headache</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/12/20/eclipsecfeclipse-gives-me-a-headache/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2006 04:39:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/12/20/eclipsecfeclipse-gives-me-a-headache/</guid>
      <description>So I know I&amp;rsquo;m going to get a hard time from the die hard eclipse lovers out there. Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, eclipse (or more precisely for me cfeclipse) is free to use and at that cost you can&amp;rsquo;t get any cheaper which is fantastic for all ColdFusion developers :)
Also I REALLY admire Rob Rohan, Mark Drew and all the other contributors this and every other open source product. It&amp;rsquo;s people like these who truly give something of value to the community at large.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Determining which http/proxy ports your JRun instance is running on</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/12/19/determining-which-httpproxy-ports-your-jrun-instance-is-running-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2006 05:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/12/19/determining-which-httpproxy-ports-your-jrun-instance-is-running-on/</guid>
      <description>At Daemon we often run ColdFusion in multi-server mode (on top of JRun) which enables us to cleanly separate projects which require different server settings from one another.
Typically I have a ColdFusion instance per Farcry version, at the moment that would be:
 p300 (v3) gonzales (v4)  When ColdFusion first installs in multi-server mode you get the default &amp;lsquo;cfusion&amp;rsquo; instance, but you also get the &amp;lsquo;admin&amp;rsquo; JRun instance which is really only used when you need to access the JRun Management Console&amp;hellip;not very often for most people!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reseting a lost ColdFusion Administrator password</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/12/15/reseting-a-lost-coldfusion-administrator-password/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2006 02:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/12/15/reseting-a-lost-coldfusion-administrator-password/</guid>
      <description>A colleague sent me a nice way to obtain access to ColdFusion Administrator (any instance) when you&amp;rsquo;ve lost your password. After a little googling I also came across another method, both assume that you have administrator access to the application server.
The following examples assume a ColdFusion installation in a multi-server environment, using the default (cfusion) instance.
 Reseting the password:  Open the password.properties file in C:\JRun4\servers\cfusion\cfusion-ear\cfusion-war\WEB-INF\cfusion\lib Enter your new password for RDS (&amp;ldquo;rdspassword&amp;rdquo;) and ColdFusion Administrator (&amp;ldquo;password&amp;rdquo;) Make sure &amp;ldquo;encrypted&amp;rdquo; is set to false Restart your ColdFusion instance  Turning the password off (allowing full access with no authentication)  Open the neo-security.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No error handler for MXNA</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/12/13/no-error-handler-for-mxna/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2006 02:53:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/12/13/no-error-handler-for-mxna/</guid>
      <description>Funny, but I&amp;rsquo;ve had this screen many many times when accessing MXNA.
I wonder how many sites (let alone high profile sites) don&amp;rsquo;t have a default error handler in place.
Exception handling (be it with cftry/cfcatch or cferror etc) is often the last thing on a developers mind. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to assume that things won&amp;rsquo;t go wrong or the user will enter the correct data in a form.
One of the things I strive to do as a developer is to think of the worst case scenario, or to think like a hacker/malicious user.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outputting content from within a method</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/12/12/outputting-content-from-within-a-method/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2006 22:47:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/12/12/outputting-content-from-within-a-method/</guid>
      <description>Normally I&amp;rsquo;m with the crowd who says &amp;ldquo;don&amp;rsquo;t output content or use  from within a function&amp;rdquo;. Like a lot of people I would much rather return whatever value I need to the calling page/function, so that I then have a choice with what I want to do with it.
Still, the other day I found myself doing what I don&amp;rsquo;t normally do&amp;hellip;wanting to output a simple text value from within a method.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Including js files from within js files</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/12/07/including-js-files-from-within-js-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/12/07/including-js-files-from-within-js-files/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m working on an application which stores a lot of data in the application scope. Part of the data stored is a config CFC that has a method which loads &amp;lsquo;external assets&amp;rsquo; (javascript and css files etc) into the  of the html document via . I love that tag :)
My part in this application development is limited to a particular section only, but there was already a lot of external assets present in the header and things were getting very messy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>snap...a google competitor and cool site preview tool</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/12/05/snapa-google-competitor-and-cool-site-preview-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2006 06:20:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/12/05/snapa-google-competitor-and-cool-site-preview-tool/</guid>
      <description>Snap is a nice little search engine which displays your results in a left window pane and a site preview of your search result in the right. It&amp;rsquo;s very Ajax-y and includes personalised settings, email a friend, result ratings and more. They even made the Time 50 coolest websites of 2006.
Snap is also a free preview tool for your website which enables visitors to catch a glimpse of what websites you are linking to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Viewing AJAX generated source code</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/12/04/viewing-ajax-generated-source-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2006 12:13:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/12/04/viewing-ajax-generated-source-code/</guid>
      <description>When developing for the web there is often a need to view the (X)HTML source code of a page to see exactly what ColdFusion (or your server side language of choice) is generating from the server.
One of the problems you might face is when viewing the source code of an AJAX generated event. Of course AJAX being asynchronous means that the page doesn&amp;rsquo;t reload in the browser, so viewing the source code doesn&amp;rsquo;t allow us to see the content which was generated by our AJAX call.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Will CFMX8 have cfcontinue?</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/11/29/will-cfmx8-have-cfcontinue/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2006 04:13:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/11/29/will-cfmx8-have-cfcontinue/</guid>
      <description>There are a couple of nice statements you can use to control processing within loops, namely
 break continue  Break is of course used to exit the current loop entirely and resume page processing from the first CF statement after the end loop tag. Lovely!
Continue has a subtle but handy difference, it ends the current loop iteration and &amp;lsquo;continues&amp;rsquo; from the beginning of the next loop iteration. Very lovely :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commenting templates with author data</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/11/16/commenting-templates-with-author-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2006 02:55:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/11/16/commenting-templates-with-author-data/</guid>
      <description>We all know that we should liberally comment our code to allow other developers (and yourself) to quickly and easily find out what a particular section of code does. But what about a comment block at the top of the page so anybody can (at a glance) determine template specific information?
Here is an example of what I use at the top of my pages, this is pretty standard but I know a lot of people don&amp;rsquo;t do it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting tag functionality in cfscript</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/11/15/getting-tag-functionality-in-cfscript/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2006 08:56:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/11/15/getting-tag-functionality-in-cfscript/</guid>
      <description>For some developers there is an age old argument between the use of ColdFusion tags and &amp;lt;cfscript&amp;gt;, I&amp;rsquo;m not going to delve too much into this argument as I believe you can use both for different scenarios.
What I will say is that I do like many things about &amp;lt;cfscript&amp;gt;. It is easy to read and arguably more elegant and concise. Of course the annoying thing is that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have the full feature set of tags&amp;hellip;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wordpress RSS feed validation</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/11/14/wordpress-rss-feed-validation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2006 22:15:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/11/14/wordpress-rss-feed-validation/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Wordpress for a while now and I&amp;rsquo;m really happy with it. Only recently have I tried to validate my RSS feed using feedvalidator.
Unfortunately even though the feed validated I received the following warning:
 wfw:commentRSS should be wfw:commentRss
 The explanation given on the site was:
 Due to a clerical error, the element Chris Sells originally spec&amp;rsquo;ed as wfw:commentRss appeared as wfw:commentRSS (note the difference in case) on Joe Gregorio&amp;rsquo;s site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lightweight Notepad replacements</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/11/13/lightweight-notepad-replacements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2006 23:26:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/11/13/lightweight-notepad-replacements/</guid>
      <description>Usually when developing you have all your relevant development files contained within a central project directory, so you can of course access any file you want from within your IDE environment.
Sometimes however (and this is very often for me) you want to open a file (or bunch of files) which don&amp;rsquo;t exist in a current &amp;lsquo;project&amp;rsquo;, or you may want a scratch pad to work with for quick notes. Those familiar with eclipse (and cfeclipse) will recognise that this can be troublesome as you can&amp;rsquo;t easily open a file which is outside a project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reserved characters in HTML &#39;id&#39; attribute</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/11/09/reserved-characters-in-html-id-attribute/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2006 06:22:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/11/09/reserved-characters-in-html-id-attribute/</guid>
      <description>Currently I&amp;rsquo;m building an app which will accept metadata from different sources, translate that into an API to dynamically build an HTML form from. Everything is going just dandy until my page stopped validating (I use tidy to validate my markup) when I got the following warning:
After some digging I discovered that the value of the &amp;lsquo;id&amp;rsquo; attribute in not simply a string which you can put anything into. I found this on w3c:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cheap ColdFusion hosting?</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/11/09/cheap-coldfusion-hosting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2006 02:29:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/11/09/cheap-coldfusion-hosting/</guid>
      <description>ColdFusion hosting (shared) certainly isn&amp;rsquo;t as ubiquitous as say PHP, but there are some well known hosting providers that you can use particuarly for smaller clients on a budget.
Some of the more popular ones are Hostmysite and Crystal Tech. Last week some colleagues turned me on to Hosting A to Z who are the cheapest I&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen, with prices as low as USD$34.99 a year (not a month&amp;hellip;a year!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Browser testing your site design</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/11/08/browser-testing-your-site-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2006 01:59:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/11/08/browser-testing-your-site-design/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve often used browsercam for testing my sites in different browsers on different operating systems. So I can pass a URL (which must be publicly available) and see screenshot results on Windows, Linux and Mac across just about any browser you like&amp;hellip;from Flock to Firefox and Safari to Konqueror. A full browser list can be seen here.
Now browsercam is also cool because it lets you devicecheck, meaning testing your site on Blackberries or Windows Mobile&amp;hellip;nice :) Only problem is that browsercam is commercial, so if you&amp;rsquo;re a sole trader you may not have the budget for what is such an ESSENTIAL part of web development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Caching stored procedures</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/11/08/caching-stored-procedures/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2006 01:29:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/11/08/caching-stored-procedures/</guid>
      <description>Stored procedures are great for many reasons but one of the reasons I might not use them is you can&amp;rsquo;t cache them&amp;hellip;or can you?
A discussion at work enlightened me to a simple way around the lack of the cachedwithin attribute inside the  tag. Simply use the  tag instead!
Ok, so normally if I wanted to use a stored procedure I might do something like:
&amp;lt;cfstoredproc procedure=&amp;quot;qGetUser&amp;quot; datasource=&amp;quot;#application.dsn#&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;cfprocparam cfsqltype=&amp;quot;CF_SQL_INTEGER&amp;quot; null=&amp;quot;false&amp;quot; type=&amp;quot;in&amp;quot; value=&amp;quot;#arguments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you know about Alexa Internet?</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/11/06/do-you-know-about-alexa-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2006 01:17:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/11/06/do-you-know-about-alexa-internet/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Along the way Alexa has developed an installed based of millions of toolbars, one of the largest Web crawls and an infrastructure to process and serve massive amounts of data.&amp;rdquo;
 Alexa Internet was founded in 1996, why does this matter to anyone? Well one reason is their page rankings, often used as an indication of just how popular a web site is. Of course you need to take into account that the statistics provided by Alexa are only available from users (of which there are millions!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alternatives to Adobe ColdFusion server?</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/11/06/adobe-alternatives-to-coldfusion-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/11/06/adobe-alternatives-to-coldfusion-server/</guid>
      <description>For as long as I can remember there has been heated discussions regarding the cost of ColdFusion server (both Standard and Enterprise). Because that topic has been beaten to death I won&amp;rsquo;t go into the particulars or the perceived pros and cons of the cost element with ColdFusion.
For me as a ColdFusion developer I want to know that my job (and future) are secure in my current technology of choice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogging problems with my (PHP) host</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/11/03/blogging-problems-my-php-host/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2006 06:39:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/11/03/blogging-problems-my-php-host/</guid>
      <description>Last week my blog software decided to stop working. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t create or edit any posts, bugger.
It wasn&amp;rsquo;t the fault of the blog software however, it seems the host added some new &amp;lsquo;forbidden&amp;rsquo; words to their list and of course I wasn&amp;rsquo;t notified.
Basically every time I wanted to create or edit a post I was redirected to the host&amp;rsquo;s home page! Specifically it looks like the line in question which was causing me headaches was:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cfeclipse snippets</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/10/22/cfeclipse-snippets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2006 01:13:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/10/22/cfeclipse-snippets/</guid>
      <description>The eclipse/cfeclipse combinations makes for a pretty powerfull developing tool for ColdFusion programmers, even those who miss the good old days of using Homesite!
One of the cool things cfeclipse brought over from Homesite is snippets, but cfeclipse has a few extra goodies to make them better than ever :)
Whereas in Homesite you would assign a keyboard shortcut directly to a snippet, cfeclipse has an invoke/trigger key combination which stays the same while allowing you to use ANY key(s) as the actual trigger text for the snippet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building accessible tables</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/10/20/building-accessible-tables/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2006 04:37:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/10/20/building-accessible-tables/</guid>
      <description>These days all the rage is building web pages without tables, but has this gone too far for a lot of developers?
I&amp;rsquo;m of the opinion that HTML tables shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be used for layout purposes and I think most would agree, if you don&amp;rsquo;t please let me know because I&amp;rsquo;d love to hear the reasoning :)
There is however a quite valid and obvious for using tables, that being where the content contains tabular data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>varScoper 1.0 has been released</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/10/18/varscoper-10-has-been-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2006 22:31:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/10/18/varscoper-10-has-been-released/</guid>
      <description>Today Mike Schierberl released his varScoper 1.0 tool for identifying variables that haven&amp;rsquo;t been locally scoped within cffunctions (whether they be in .cfm or .cfc files).
Looks like there may be some slight tweaking for *nix systems or macs, and there is no cfscript support but all in all a great tool. I bet you&amp;rsquo;d be surprised at how many variables you are using in your functions which aren&amp;rsquo;t var scoped!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making ColdFusion sleep</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/10/17/making-coldfusion-sleep/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/10/17/making-coldfusion-sleep/</guid>
      <description>Often times you want the server to pause execution of a page, or go to sleep for a short while. You may be waiting for a file to be written to the file system etc.
You can do achieve this in the following fashion:
&amp;lt;cfset createObject(&#39;java&#39;, &#39;java.lang.Thread&#39;).sleep(5000) /&amp;gt;  The example above makes the server call &amp;ldquo;sleep&amp;rdquo; for 5 seconds.
Ryan Duckworth states:
 &amp;ldquo;A java thread (which ColdFusion code is converted to) is doing a NOP (no operation) procedure during a java Sleep command which causes no inefficiency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Validating a user defined password with reg exp</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/10/14/validating-a-user-defined-password-with-reg-exp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2006 23:17:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/10/14/validating-a-user-defined-password-with-reg-exp/</guid>
      <description>A nice little reg exp from the ColdFusion Cookbook when you need to make sure a users new password (which they are setting) contains at least 1 letter and 1 number.
You can also make sure the password length is within a range, the following makes sure the password is between 6 and 15 characters long.
&amp;lt;cfif NOT reFind(&amp;quot;^[[:alnum:]]{6,15}$&amp;quot;, form.sPassword) /&amp;gt;  Don&amp;rsquo;t you just love regular expressions :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When not to use this.form.submit()</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/10/12/when-not-to-use-thisformsubmit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/10/12/when-not-to-use-thisformsubmit/</guid>
      <description>So ok, I&amp;rsquo;ve run into this problem in the past where I&amp;rsquo;m using an onclick event to submit a form from a button control. When you click the button you get a nice little Javascript error stating:
 this.form.submit is not a function
 Bugger&amp;hellip;wtf?
This only seems to happen when you have a form element named &amp;ldquo;submit&amp;rdquo; already on your page, so the browser treats that &amp;ldquo;submit&amp;rdquo; element as an object which is of course NOT a function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paginating with SQL Server 2005</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/10/10/paginating-with-sql-server-2005/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2006 23:02:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/10/10/paginating-with-sql-server-2005/</guid>
      <description>Adam Howitt blogged recently about Pagination made easier with SQL Server 2005, have a read of his post and take the time to implement the solution as most pagination scripts I&amp;rsquo;ve seen are lazy and don&amp;rsquo;t perform well&amp;hellip;particularly with a lot of content!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regular Expressions in JavaScript</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/10/06/regular-expressions-in-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2006 12:31:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/10/06/regular-expressions-in-javascript/</guid>
      <description>All about regular expressions, particularly for javascript!
click here for more</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google code search</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/10/06/google-code-search/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2006 12:29:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/10/06/google-code-search/</guid>
      <description>Google have come out with yet another fantastic tool, particularly for the developers out there :)
google code search was released yesterday as a beta in google labs to search for public source code.
You can read more here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>double-checked locking</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/10/05/double-checked-locking-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2006 23:09:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/10/05/double-checked-locking-2/</guid>
      <description>Mark Kruger details a concept (with a little help from Sean Corfield) known as &amp;ldquo;double-checked locking&amp;rdquo;, in the example as it pertains to application scoped variables.
The basic premise is that normally you would put &amp;lt;cfif NOT structKeyExists(application, “myVar”)&amp;gt; logic around you setting of application variables. If the application variable(s) didn’t exist you would have a &amp;lt;cflock&amp;gt; within the &amp;lt;cfif&amp;gt; to perform locking while you write your application variables.
However what would happen when 2 threads (2 users) hit that logic/lock at the same time?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Broken image on Google search results page</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/10/05/broken-image-on-google-search-results-page/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2006 02:01:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/10/05/broken-image-on-google-search-results-page/</guid>
      <description>Funny when the big guys get something wrong :)
I noticed this today on the google.com.au search results page; a nice little broken image!
Bugger!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High CPU and memory usage in ColdFusion</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/10/04/finding-cpu-andor-memory-leak-issues-with-coldfusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/10/04/finding-cpu-andor-memory-leak-issues-with-coldfusion/</guid>
      <description>Charlie Arehart had an extremely interesting article today on JRun performance issues, particularly relating to high CPU cycles and memory usage.
The perpetrators in this example were thought to be search engine spiders (or &amp;lsquo;bots&amp;rsquo;) and/or RSS feeds.
Now bots may visit your website many times throughout the course of a single day, this could be the same bot of different bots (for different search engines). Also you may be in a situation where you have many people syndicating content from your site in the form of a feed (RSS/Atom etc).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mach-II 1.1.1 Public Beta2</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/10/03/mach-ii-111-public-beta2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2006 23:20:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/10/03/mach-ii-111-public-beta2/</guid>
      <description>The peeps over at Mach-II have been busy with the latest dot release of the Mach-II framework. Last week they released the Public Beta2 for 1.1.1 which you can download here.
A big note for Version 1.1.1 is Application.cfc support :)
Although Mach-II is a well known framework in the community it seems that Model Glue is getting all the attention lately. With that in mind I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking forward to new releases from the Mach-II side.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Standards - rooting for the underdog</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/10/02/web-standards-rooting-for-the-underdog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2006 23:20:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/10/02/web-standards-rooting-for-the-underdog/</guid>
      <description>Roger Johansson wrote a nice article on why web standards still matter. He notes that recently there has been an increased level of interest and activity around web standards, but those that do strive for excellence in their code (i.e. web standards) are in the extreme minority.
I would tend to agree with this, take his example:
 I encourage anyone who thinks we do not need yet another article or book on Web standards, CSS, accessibility, graceful degradation, progressive enhancement, or anything else related to best practices, to take a quick look around you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Javascript function properties</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/10/01/javascript-function-properties/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2006 00:43:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/10/01/javascript-function-properties/</guid>
      <description>Javascript is pretty cool and I&amp;rsquo;ll admit that I don&amp;rsquo;t get to do as much as I&amp;rsquo;d like with it. Today I&amp;rsquo;m going to briefly cover a few properties of any Javascript function which you can take advantage of:
 arguments callee arity  arguments The arguments property contains an array of input parameters which may be passed to the function. It can be used to determine how many variables are being passed in and what they are, without each argument being explicitly declared in the function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Firefox Web Developer Toolbar</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/09/29/firefox-web-developer-toolbar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2006 01:11:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/09/29/firefox-web-developer-toolbar/</guid>
      <description>Scott Stroz (aka boyzoid) has a nice little post on the Firefox Web Developer Toolbar by Chris Pederick.
The toolbar (which has been around for ages) is a must have for any web developer, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d post some of the tools including their shortcuts which I use regularly.
CSS Viewing CSS - Ctrl+Shift+C
Opens up a new tab with the current pages CSS. I also use the [JSView](https://addons.mozilla.org/firefox/2076/) for this because it lets you view and individual Javascript or CSS files  View Style Information - Ctrl+Shift+Y</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Javascript parseInt() quirk</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/09/28/javascript-parseint-quirk/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2006 07:45:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/09/28/javascript-parseint-quirk/</guid>
      <description>I ran into a little quirk or &amp;lsquo;bug&amp;rsquo; today when using parseInt() with a string (input from a text box). Now as we all know parseInt() parses a string and returns an integer value.
The scenario: I was working on a legacy application where a user could pass a date to the server in 3 separate form fields (day, month and year); all text boxes. No nice little DHTML calendars here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cfhtmlhead</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/09/25/cfhtmlhead/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2006 00:44:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/09/25/cfhtmlhead/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes during development you may want to programmatically add text/content to the &amp;lt;head&amp;gt; area of the currently processing page. Most often I do this when I want to add Javascript code or link tags dynamically.
&amp;lt;cfhtmlhead&amp;gt; is a great tool to use for this as you don’t need to try and spaghetti code your header include/module.
For example:
&amp;lt;cfhtmlhead text=&amp;quot;&amp;lt;script type=&amp;quot;text/javascript&amp;quot; src=&amp;quot;/js/myScript.js&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;  TEXT
The text you want to add to the &amp;lt;head&amp;gt; area of an HTML page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trimming strings with Javascript</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/09/19/trimming-strings-with-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2006 23:23:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/09/19/trimming-strings-with-javascript/</guid>
      <description>Ben Nadel has a nice post on trimming strings with javascript using regular expressions.
Note that the reg exp white space character &amp;lsquo;\s&amp;rsquo; is used to match:
 space tab horizontal tab vertical tab line break  Sample code below:
&amp;lt;script type=&amp;quot;text/javascript&amp;quot;&amp;gt; // Trims the beginning and trailing white space from a string. function trim( strText ){ return( strText.replace(new RegExp(&amp;quot;^([s]+)|([s]+)$&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;gm&amp;quot;), &amp;quot;&amp;quot;) ); } // Trims the beinning white space from a string.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robots META tag</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/09/12/robots-meta-tag/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2006 23:35:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/09/12/robots-meta-tag/</guid>
      <description>The Robots META tag is a way you can tell &amp;lsquo;Robots&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;Spiders&amp;rsquo; whether a page (or pages) on your site should be indexed, or if links on the page should be followed.
At this stage I don&amp;rsquo;t believe all &amp;lsquo;robots&amp;rsquo; out there support the use of this META tag, but some do so in the right situation it&amp;rsquo;s worth using.
The most common examples for the robots META tags are:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hostmysite.com and ColdFusion mappings</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/09/11/hostmysitecom-and-coldfusion-mappings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2006 00:31:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/09/11/hostmysitecom-and-coldfusion-mappings/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently gotten myself a hostmysite account on a shared server for a project I&amp;rsquo;m involved with. Everything looked fantastic and they certainly have a great reputation in the community.
Before signing on the dotted line I wanted to make sure everything was in order including:
 ColdFusion; Enterprise or Standard?
 Multiple CF mappings?
 Web mappings?
 Multiple DSN&amp;rsquo;s?
 Are any CF tags disabled etc
 Server specs etc</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cfcomponent - should you use the name=&#34;&#34; attribute?</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/09/10/cfcomponent-should-you-use-the-name-attribute/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2006 23:29:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/09/10/cfcomponent-should-you-use-the-name-attribute/</guid>
      <description>Charlie Arehart has an interesting post here on whether you should use the name attribute in cfcomponent.
Apparently there is no &amp;lsquo;name&amp;rsquo; attrbribute in the cfdocs for &amp;lt;cfcomponent&amp;gt;, remember you can use displayName or hint for component introspection. And if you want to take advantage of getMetaData()? Well there already is a &amp;lsquo;name&amp;rsquo; attribute as default in ColdFusionMX! The thing is that&amp;rsquo;s it&amp;rsquo;s for internal use and even if you do use &amp;lsquo;name&amp;rsquo;, the value you specify won&amp;rsquo;t appear in getMetaData(), the internal ColdFusion value will instead!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTML strip</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/09/09/html-strip/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2006 03:19:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/09/09/html-strip/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s say you have a form or mechanism in a web application which allows users to enter content which may be displayed on a web page, a comment area for example.
In these scenarios you need to be carefull of what my be entered by a malicious user, think cross site scripting. There are various reg exp’s available to assist you in cleaning the data but good folks a Adobe have given us a nice little function in htmlEditFormat().</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CFC Bean generators</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/09/07/cfc-bean-generators/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2006 00:55:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/09/07/cfc-bean-generators/</guid>
      <description>There are a few Bean generators around for ColdFusion which can save you a lot if time and effort when you need to create your CFC Beans, here are a few making the rounds.
Jonathan Block
A more advanced generator which creates init() and validate() functions for you. For the picky developers out there you might want to tidy things up a bit. Example the ‘set’ in the init() misses a space at the end of the</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Server settings with Java</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/09/07/server-settings-with-java/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2006 00:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/09/07/server-settings-with-java/</guid>
      <description>Here are a couple of ways which you can determine the name of the JRun instance you are running as well as the server name of the Application server. Here at Daemon we use these quite a bit in our more complex project environments.
&amp;lt;!--- get the machine (server) name ---&amp;gt; &amp;lt;cfset variables.serverName = createObject(&amp;quot;java&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;java.net.InetAddress&amp;quot;).localhost.getHostName() /&amp;gt; &amp;lt;!--- get the JRun instance name ---&amp;gt; &amp;lt;cfset variables.instanceName = createObject(&amp;quot;java&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;jrunx.kernel.JRun&amp;quot;).getServerName() /&amp;gt; &amp;lt;cfoutput&amp;gt; Server: #variables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dashboard Confessional</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/09/06/dashboard-confessional/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2006 14:11:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/09/06/dashboard-confessional/</guid>
      <description>Tonight (well last night considering the time at the moment!) I went to see Dashboard Confessional at the Hordern Pavillion.
Not a bad show, I am a fan but not a huge one. His voice is quite unique and I like a lot of their tunes. A strong band with good vocals all round. I&amp;rsquo;d go a 6.5 out of 10
It was interesting being there considering my age and the average age of the people around me&amp;hellip;I felt old!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-step forms</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/09/05/multi-step-forms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2006 23:23:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/09/05/multi-step-forms/</guid>
      <description>Rahul Narula has a great post on Multi-step forms. As web developers forms are a part of our everyday lives, sometimes those forms exist over several pages instead of 1 looong page. That being said we need a way to hold the data entered by the user at each step (page) thoughout the process.
We can of course use either of the following:
 Database Session scope Structures URL  There are probably more but that would be all I would consider (at this stage!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Busy at the moment?</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/09/02/busy-at-the-moment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2006 03:45:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/09/02/busy-at-the-moment/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Time is the tiny bits of space between one busy moment and the next.&amp;rdquo;
 A friend wrote this and got me thinking, I don&amp;rsquo;t know about you but I am always SO busy these days. I used to think that I was just having a busy week or a busy month. Nup&amp;hellip;that&amp;rsquo;s life :)
It makes you wonder when you&amp;rsquo;ll have time to &amp;lsquo;enjoy&amp;rsquo; life, so much time is spent at work or doing chores or stuck in traffic etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Memory lane</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/09/01/memory-lane/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2006 13:34:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/09/01/memory-lane/</guid>
      <description>So last night we went to see Richard Marx at the Capitol. Yeah&amp;hellip;I know what you&amp;rsquo;re thinking but that&amp;rsquo;s ok, I&amp;rsquo;m not afraid to say that I&amp;rsquo;m a fan and have been for a long time!
Yes it&amp;rsquo;s true I like his voice and his songs, but what I really like is his production and studio band. He always uses the cream of the session muso pool including;
 Michael Thompson Michael Landau Bruce Gaitsch John Moffet Lee Sklar Jeff Porcaro Steve Lukather  Phew&amp;hellip;that&amp;rsquo;s quite a list!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTML pre-launch flight check</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/08/25/html-pre-launch-flight-check/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2006 02:49:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/08/25/html-pre-launch-flight-check/</guid>
      <description>AnyBrowser have a lot of tools for you to use when validating and preparing your website for deployment including:
 Screen Size Test
 Meta Tag Creator
 HTML Validation
 Link checking
 Engine View (See how your site might get listed by search engine spiders.)
  Not a bad list, don&amp;rsquo;t forget that ALL web developers should validate their pages, perform link checking and test on different resolutions before going live.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A London gift</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/08/12/a-londonn-gift/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2006 13:38:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/08/12/a-londonn-gift/</guid>
      <description>Carl Orr is in town but only for a few days. Carl is truly a special guitarist and an old teacher of mine. In fact I even did his original wesite waaaay back in the day (please forgive it now!). Carl has been living in London for about 10 years so it was a long time coming considering I used to see him play almost every other week in the mid 90&amp;rsquo;s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SWFObject</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/08/01/swfobject/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2006 03:27:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/08/01/swfobject/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been using SWFObject for quite a while now and it amazes me that developers out there still don&amp;rsquo;t know about it, especially with all the news around Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s EOLAS case late last year.
SWFObject is a tasty method for embedding Macromedia Flash content into your web pages and has (among others) the following functionality which alone are reason to be using it!
 Flash detection Search engine friendly Validates to HTML and XHTML (as long as pages sent as text/html, not application/xhtml+xml.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Truncating MSSQL transaction log</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/07/26/truncating-mssql-transaction-log/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2006 05:32:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/07/26/truncating-mssql-transaction-log/</guid>
      <description>Every wanted to truncate the transaction log of a MS SQL database? We do that all the time when moving a database from one server to the other. Remember that the transaction log can take up a LOT of space in the backup file which you don&amp;rsquo;t need when you are simply moving a database to a new server (and when you don&amp;rsquo;t have the option to simply DTS).
Open up Query Analyser and run the following, substituting real database, file and log names.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Semantic named anchors</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/07/17/33/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2006 08:22:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/07/17/33/</guid>
      <description>bitesizestandards have a nice article on &amp;lsquo;semantic anchors&amp;rsquo; which are used to link to different areas of the current page you are viewing.
The usual way we all do this is with a named anchor as follows, &amp;lsquo;Name&amp;rsquo; a content area on your page:
&amp;lt;a name=&amp;quot;myContent&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;  Add the link to that content area
&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;#myContent&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Go to myContent&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;  The problem is that this isn&amp;rsquo;t semantic and it&amp;rsquo;s not ideal to have empty &amp;lt;a href&amp;gt; elements on your page (&amp;lt;a name=&amp;ldquo;&amp;rdquo;&amp;gt;).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache, are you secure?</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/07/16/apache-are-you-secure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2006 05:15:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/07/16/apache-are-you-secure/</guid>
      <description>Peter Freitag has a great post on &amp;lsquo;20 ways to secure your Apache Configuration&amp;rsquo;
Seeing as Apache is a rather popular web server, this is invaluable information for any developer particularly those who are involved with configuring production boxes.
Just how popular is Apache? Have a look at Netcrafts Web Server Survey to September 2006.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flash of Unstyled Content</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/06/20/flash-of-unstyled-content/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2006 08:41:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/06/20/flash-of-unstyled-content/</guid>
      <description>The lovely people (person?) over at Blue Robot have coined a term &amp;lsquo;FOUC&amp;rsquo;; or Flash of Unstyled Content.
This is that annoying &amp;lsquo;bug&amp;rsquo; in Windows IE where a user can see the entire body of the page their trying to view &amp;lsquo;unstyled&amp;rsquo; (particularly for page layout) for a moment before the stylesheet kicks in. If the CSS is cached then you probably won&amp;rsquo;t see this happen, but for first time users this just looks amature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Determining machine name using java</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/05/06/determining-machine-name-using-java/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2006 07:33:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/05/06/determining-machine-name-using-java/</guid>
      <description>Often when you are developing in a team environment you will be using the same code base checked in and out of a source control repository (SVN, CVS etc). Sometimes you may have problems with developers having a different machine configuration than you do when these settings are stored as variables in a project config file.
One way we do things at Daemon is:
&amp;lt;cfset machineName=createObject(&amp;quot;java&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;java.net.InetAddress&amp;quot;).localhost.getHostName() /&amp;gt; &amp;lt;cfswitch expression=&amp;quot;#machinename#&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;cfcase value=&amp;quot;sharmo&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;cfset myVar = &amp;quot;test&amp;quot; /&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/cfcase&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/cfswitch&amp;gt;  This way each developer can script his or her own machine specific configuration in a case statement and not have a problem when checking into source control because everyone’s config is in the same file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dumping and aborting with &lt;cfscript&gt;</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/04/28/dumping-and-aborting-with/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2006 05:01:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/04/28/dumping-and-aborting-with/</guid>
      <description>One of the annoying things about cfscript is it&amp;rsquo;s lack of support for a lot of CFML tags.
 and  are 2 tags I always use in development, especially for debugging. A way to use this functionality is to create a UDF to do these types of functions.
For example
&amp;lt;cffunction name=&amp;quot;dump&amp;quot; access=&amp;quot;public&amp;quot; output=&amp;quot;true&amp;quot; returntype=&amp;quot;struct&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;cfargument name=&amp;quot;arg&amp;quot; /&amp;gt; &amp;lt;cfdump var=&amp;quot;#arg#&amp;quot; /&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/cffunction&amp;gt; &amp;lt;cffunction name=&amp;quot;abort&amp;quot; access=&amp;quot;public&amp;quot; output=&amp;quot;false&amp;quot; returntype=&amp;quot;void&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;cfabort /&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/cffunction&amp;gt;  This function can be stored in a simple utilities component and stored in application scope, that way you can call it from anywhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>isValid()</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/04/20/isvalid/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2006 03:28:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/04/20/isvalid/</guid>
      <description>New to ColdFusion MX7 the isValid() function tests whether a value meets a validation or data type rule and returns True if the value conforms to the rule; False, otherwise.
Function syntax
isValid(type, value) isValid(&amp;quot;range&amp;quot;, value, min, max) isValid(&amp;quot;regex&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;regular_expression&amp;quot;, value, pattern)  Example:
&amp;lt;cfif IsValid(&amp;quot;integer&amp;quot;, url.value)&amp;gt; Valid integer! &amp;lt;cfelse&amp;gt; Invalid Integer! &amp;lt;/cfif&amp;gt; &amp;lt;cfif IsValid(&amp;quot;range&amp;quot;, url.value, 1, 100)&amp;gt; Value is between 1 and 100 &amp;lt;cfelse&amp;gt; Value is not between 1 and 100 &amp;lt;/cfif&amp;gt; &amp;lt;cfif IsValid(&amp;quot;regex&amp;quot;, url.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cfdump goodies</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/04/11/cfdump-goodies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2006 05:56:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/04/11/cfdump-goodies/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt;cfdump&amp;gt; is a fantastic debugging tool which can be used to display the values/results of simple and complex variables. But there are a couple of little known attributes you can take advantage of to make your life just peachy, namely:
 expand top  Expand is great when you&amp;rsquo;re working with large data structures which might take a long time to load etc. This attribute can take 2 values, either yes or no (the default being yes).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do I trim the contents of a form?</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/04/01/how-do-i-trim-the-contents-of-a-form/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2006 05:27:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/04/01/how-do-i-trim-the-contents-of-a-form/</guid>
      <description>From ColdFusion Cookbook:
Trimming is an essential part of dealing with an data coming from form textfields or textareas etc. You can of couse trim as and when you need (before validation or database inserts etc) but if you can trim all fields quickly and easily!
&amp;lt;cfloop collection=&amp;quot;#form#&amp;quot; item=&amp;quot;formfield&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;cfset form[formfield] = trim(form[formfield]) /&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/cfloop&amp;gt;  This basically loops over a form structure and trims each element. You can use this loop in a function before handing it to your validation or database methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to find the size of a directory?</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/03/31/how-to-find-the-size-of-a-directory/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2006 01:36:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/03/31/how-to-find-the-size-of-a-directory/</guid>
      <description>Here is an article from coldfusion cookbook.
&amp;lt;cfdirectory directory=&amp;quot;c:\cfusionmx&amp;quot; action=&amp;quot;list&amp;quot; recurse=&amp;quot;true&amp;quot; name=&amp;quot;cfDir&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;cfquery dbtype=&amp;quot;query&amp;quot; name=&amp;quot;dirSize&amp;quot;&amp;gt; select sum(size) as size from cfDir &amp;lt;/cfquery&amp;gt; &amp;lt;cfset sizemb=&amp;quot;dirSize.size/1000000&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;cfoutput&amp;gt;#numberFormat(sizeMB,&amp;quot;,.99&amp;quot;)#&amp;lt;/cfoutput&amp;gt;  Note the &amp;lsquo;recurse&amp;rsquo; option, this will get the size of the current and all sub-directories. If you only need the size of the current directory, change recurse to false.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do I make sure a string is safe to use with JavaScript?</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/03/29/how-do-i-make-sure-a-string-is-safe-to-use-with-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2006 01:45:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/03/29/how-do-i-make-sure-a-string-is-safe-to-use-with-javascript/</guid>
      <description>An article from coldfusion cookbook using jSStringFormat():
&amp;ldquo;If you are dynamically populating a JavaScript variable, you may find that your code breaks with &amp;ldquo;unterminated string constant&amp;rdquo; or similar error messages. This is probably a case of your JavaScript variables containing characters that are considers to be &amp;ldquo;special&amp;rdquo; characters by JavaScript. You will need to &amp;ldquo;escape&amp;rdquo; these special characters so that JavaScript can process them.&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cfstoredproc vs cfquery</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/03/16/cfstoredproc-vs-cfquery/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2006 00:30:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/03/16/cfstoredproc-vs-cfquery/</guid>
      <description>There are of course pros and cons to using each method to perform CRUD operations on a database.
cfstoredproc Pros:
 With stored procedures you can control security in the database as well as the web pages. Transactions are handled at the database level, stored procedures are ideal here. Stored procedures provide greater performance, because the execution plan for the sql doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be recreated and if a page has multiple calls to the database, you can combine them all in one stored procedure, meaning only one trip to and back from the db.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>new &#39;result&#39; attribute in MX7 cfstoredproc</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/03/15/cfstoredproc-in-mx7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2006 23:51:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/03/15/cfstoredproc-in-mx7/</guid>
      <description>In CFMX7 Macromedia introduced a new (and optional) attribute to the cfstoredproc tag called &amp;ldquo;result&amp;rdquo; which specifies a name for the structure in which cfstoredproc returns the statusCode and ExecutionTime variables. If set, this value replaces cfstoredproc as the prefix to use when accessing those variables.
The result attribute provides a way for stored procedures that are called from multiple pages, possibly at the same time, to avoid overwriting the results of one call with another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Double-checked locking</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/03/14/double-checked-locking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2006 23:19:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/03/14/double-checked-locking/</guid>
      <description>Mark Kruger has a nice article (with mention from Sean Corfield) on APPLICATION variable locking.
Sean basically added that in the initial example (BAD code) if 2 users hit the  condition at the same time, only one will have a lock on the code while the other will wait. The problem lies in the fact that the 2nd user is waiting for the lock to expire, then they will perform a write operation NOT checking the  condition again!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Session and client variable handling in CFMX</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/03/13/session-and-client-variable-handling-in-cfmx/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2006 04:45:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/03/13/session-and-client-variable-handling-in-cfmx/</guid>
      <description>With CFMX there are a few new features you can take advantage of in relation to session and client variable handling, namely:
 URLSessionFormat() Using UUID for the CFToken value Using J2EE Session Variables  URLSessionFormat()
We all know that using session variables primarily relies on the user have enabled cookies in their browser, otherwise you need to pass CFIDE and CFTOKEN along the URL. This can be painful as you need to ensure you pass this client identity along with every request, whether it be an</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What we need are better programmers</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/03/12/what-we-need-are-better-programmers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2006 23:49:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/03/12/what-we-need-are-better-programmers/</guid>
      <description>An interesting article by Simon Horwith on Frameworks and OOP for ColdFusion developers.
I agree that Frameworks could be a &amp;lsquo;crutch&amp;rsquo;, but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean you should stay away. I believe all developers should strive to keep their skills at the cutting edge by constant vigilence and study. Frameworks and OO design patterns can assist programmers but the choice is theirs and should be decided by the project specifications.
Read the article here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New attribute and object variable in &lt;cfquery&gt; for CFMX7</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/03/11/new-attribute-and-object-variable-in-for-cfmx7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2006 06:49:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/03/11/new-attribute-and-object-variable-in-for-cfmx7/</guid>
      <description>Ever wanted to output the actual SQL from a dynamic query you are debugging? With CFMX 7 you can do it!
There is a new attribute in the tag called “result” which specifies a name for the structure in which cfquery returns the result variables.
Then you can reference #result_name.sql# to output the actual SQL statement to the page.
Syntax
&amp;lt;cfquery name = &amp;quot;query_name&amp;quot;&amp;gt; dataSource = &amp;quot;ds_name&amp;quot; dbtype = &amp;quot;query&amp;quot; username = &amp;quot;username&amp;quot; password = &amp;quot;password&amp;quot; maxRows = &amp;quot;number&amp;quot; blockFactor = &amp;quot;blocksize&amp;quot; timeout = &amp;quot;seconds&amp;quot; cachedAfter = &amp;quot;date&amp;quot; cachedWithin = &amp;quot;timespan&amp;quot; Either of the following: debug = &amp;quot;yes&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;no&amp;quot; or: debugresult = &amp;quot;result_name&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/cfquery&amp;gt;  Variable name Description</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>