<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Life on chapter31</title>
    <link>http://chapter31.com/categories/life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Life on chapter31</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; &lt;a href=&#34;http://michaelsharman.com&#34;&gt;Michael Sharman&lt;/a&gt; 2017</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2006 14:11:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://chapter31.com/categories/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Dashboard Confessional</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/09/06/dashboard-confessional/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2006 14:11:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/09/06/dashboard-confessional/</guid>
      <description>Tonight (well last night considering the time at the moment!) I went to see Dashboard Confessional at the Hordern Pavillion.
Not a bad show, I am a fan but not a huge one. His voice is quite unique and I like a lot of their tunes. A strong band with good vocals all round. I&amp;rsquo;d go a 6.5 out of 10
It was interesting being there considering my age and the average age of the people around me&amp;hellip;I felt old!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Busy at the moment?</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/09/02/busy-at-the-moment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2006 03:45:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/09/02/busy-at-the-moment/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Time is the tiny bits of space between one busy moment and the next.&amp;rdquo;
 A friend wrote this and got me thinking, I don&amp;rsquo;t know about you but I am always SO busy these days. I used to think that I was just having a busy week or a busy month. Nup&amp;hellip;that&amp;rsquo;s life :)
It makes you wonder when you&amp;rsquo;ll have time to &amp;lsquo;enjoy&amp;rsquo; life, so much time is spent at work or doing chores or stuck in traffic etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Memory lane</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/09/01/memory-lane/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2006 13:34:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/09/01/memory-lane/</guid>
      <description>So last night we went to see Richard Marx at the Capitol. Yeah&amp;hellip;I know what you&amp;rsquo;re thinking but that&amp;rsquo;s ok, I&amp;rsquo;m not afraid to say that I&amp;rsquo;m a fan and have been for a long time!
Yes it&amp;rsquo;s true I like his voice and his songs, but what I really like is his production and studio band. He always uses the cream of the session muso pool including;
 Michael Thompson Michael Landau Bruce Gaitsch John Moffet Lee Sklar Jeff Porcaro Steve Lukather  Phew&amp;hellip;that&amp;rsquo;s quite a list!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A London gift</title>
      <link>http://chapter31.com/2006/08/12/a-londonn-gift/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2006 13:38:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chapter31.com/2006/08/12/a-londonn-gift/</guid>
      <description>Carl Orr is in town but only for a few days. Carl is truly a special guitarist and an old teacher of mine. In fact I even did his original wesite waaaay back in the day (please forgive it now!). Carl has been living in London for about 10 years so it was a long time coming considering I used to see him play almost every other week in the mid 90&amp;rsquo;s.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>